西城故事
好好看这球 射篮
Watch this shot now! Shoot, man! Go!
喷射机
- 小鸡，吱，吱，吱 - 喷射机
- Chickie! Chick, chick, chick! - Boy! Jet boy!
喷射机帮的
Jet boy!
喷射机
Jet, Jet, Jets!
- 回来 - 胆小鬼
- Come back! - Come over here! Chickens!
滚吧
Beat it!
太好了，走吧 来吧
All right, go, Jets!
雪男
Snowboy!
给我
Come on!
滚吧
Beat it!
Chico! Andale, chico!
好了，来吧
Okay, here we go! Over here, A-Rab!
喷射机！嘿，喷射机
Jets! Jets!
伯纳多！印地欧 把他们赶走，来
Bernardo! Indio! Chaco, come on!
喷射机，来！跟我来
Jets, come on! Follow me, baby.
- Mira, mira, mira! - Jets!
Andale, Chico!
来啊，来啊
Come on, Jets!
嘿，喷射机 你好
Hey, Jets! Hello!
喷射机，来啊！朱利欧 来
Jets, come on! Julio! Come on!
Jets!
来啊
Come on, boys!
来
Come on, now!
鲨鱼最烂
喷射机
Jets!
不要打了！停手 我说，不要打了
Break it up, you punks! Cut it out! Come on, guys! Break it up, I said!
不要打了！要说几次 你们这些混混才不会再打
Come on, break it up! Come on! How many times have I told you punks to cut this stuff out?
- 可不是眩克警官吗？ - 眩克警官，你今天好啊
- Why, if it ain't Lt. Schrank! - Top of the day, Lt. Schrank.
- 还有克鲁克警官 - 克鲁克警官，您今天好啊
- And Officer Krupke. - Top of the day, Officer Krupke.
- 好你个头 - 你，下来
- I'll give you the top of the head. - Hey you, get down!
- 我们在玩呢 - 充分利用这片游乐场
- But we're having such fun. - We enjoy the playground.
让我们这些被剥夺的儿童 不致在街头玩耍
See, it keeps us deprived children off of the foul city streets.
- 闭嘴 - 我们就像是在红砖道上生的
Shut up! And born like we was on the hot pavement.
- 要我敲碎你脑袋吗？ - 小约翰，过来这儿
- You wanna get your skull broke? - Hey, Baby John, come here! Come here!
哪一个波多黎各人 把你打伤的
All right! Now, which one of these Puerto Ricans bloodied you?
- 嗯，长官- -  - 哪一个？
- Sir... - Which one?
对不起，长官
Excuse me, sir.
其实…
As a matter of fact...
我们怀疑是被警察打的
we suspicion that the job was done by a cop.
- 两个警察 - 至少两个
- Two cops. - At the very least.
- 不可能 - 在美国，没有什么不可能的
Impossible. In America, nothing is impossible.
好了，聪明人 你们都听好了
All right, wise guys... now, you listen to me!
全部的人 这些街道不是你们的
All of you! You hoodlums don't own these streets.
这里有其他的地方 我要好好管一管的
And I've had all the roughhouse I'm gonna put up with around here!
你们要杀来杀去 请便！但不要在我在的时候
You wanna kill each other, kill each other! But you ain't gonna do it on my beat!
- 有没有问题 - 有，长官
- Are there any questions? - Yes, sir.
您可不可以将那段话 翻成西班牙文
Would you mind translating that into Spanish?
伯纳多，把你的人带走
Get your friends out of here, Bernardo.
请你…
And stay out!
走远一点
Please.
好吧，鲨鱼们
Okay, Sharks.
Vámonos.
好像这个社区还不够烂一样
Boy, oh boy! As if this neighborhood wasn't crummy enough!
大伙儿 我们讲理一点，嗯？
Now, look, fellas. Fellas! Look, let's be reasonable...
如果我不把这儿管好…
if I don't get a little law and order around here...
我就得到 十字路口管交通
I get busted down to a traffic corner...
我不喜欢十字路口
and your friend don't like traffic corners.
所以现在开始，你们要和 这些波多黎各人好好相处
So, that means you're gonna start makin' nice... with the PR's from now on.
好好相处！知道吗？
I said nice! Get it?
如果你们做不到…
'Cause if you don't...
让我发现你们 在我的地盘上有动作…
and I catch any of you doin' any more brawlin' in my territory...
我会揍扁你，关到牢里 让你在那儿待着等死
I'm gonna personally beat the livin' crud out of each and every one of you... and see that you go to the can and rot there!
- 克鲁克，向这些好孩子说再见 - 再见，孩子们
- Say good-bye to the nice boys, Krupke. - Good-bye, boys.
“再见，孩子们”
"Good-bye, boys."
- 吃牢饭？天哪 - “这些街道不是你们的”
Jail? Gee. "You hoodlums don't own the streets."
- “到公园去玩” - “不要践踏草坪”
Go play in the park. Keep off of the grass.
- “出去房子外面” - “不要在这条街上”
- Get out of the house! - Keep off the block.
- “出去” - “离开世界！”
- Get outta here. - Keep off the world!
没有地盘的帮派 什么都不是
A gang that don't own the street is nothin'!
这是我们的地盘
We do own it!
来吧，喷射机，集合
Come on, Jets, round out!
- 不是指你，所有其他的人！滚吧 - 芮夫，让我加入
- Not you, Anybodys! Beat it! - Riff, you gotta let me in the gang!
你没看到我吗？我很帅 我是杀手，我要打架
Didn't you just see me? I was smash! I'm a killer, I wanna fight.
她没别的办法让男人碰她
How else she gonna get a guy to touch her?
- 你这脏老鼠 - 小女孩，走人！上路
- You dirty rat! - Come on, the road, little girl! The road!
滚吧
Beat it!
- 滚吧 - 好了，来
- Beat it! - Okay, come on.
我们很辛苦拿下这地盘的 不会就这样放弃的
Okay, now listen! Now, we fought hard for this turf, and we ain't just gonna give it up.
翡翠帮宣称是他们的，但被打败了 老鹰帮曾想染指但没成功
The Emeralds claimed it, we shot 'em out. The Hawks, remember? They tried to take it away, we knocked them down the cellar.
- 这些波多黎各人不一样 - 他们增加得很快
- But these PR's are different. - They multiply. Like cockroaches.
- 吃掉所有的食物 - 呼吸了所有的空气
- Shut the door! - They're eatin' all the food. - Breathin' all the air.
- 救命！我被墨西哥菜淹死了 - 你听到眩克警官说的话了：
- Help! I'm drowning in tamale. And you heard what that Lt. Schrank said...
我们必须要和他们和平相处
we gotta make nice with them Puerto Ricans or else.
我们眼睁睁地看着他们 把一切夺走
We gotta let 'em move in right under our noses... - and take it all away from us or else. - No!
你说的对，绝不
You're damn right, no!
那我们要怎么办？ 我告诉你怎么办
So what're we gonna do, buddy boys? I'll tell you what we're gonna do.
我们动作要快
We're gonna speed back!
要如闪电一般 一次把鲨鱼帮剿清
We're gonna move like lightnin', and we're gonna clean them Sharks up... once and for all.
让他们再不会踏入我们的地盘
So they ain't never gonna set foot on our turf again!
一次就把他们打败
We're gonna do it in one all-out fight.
- 大干一场 - 冷静下来，猛男
- A rumble! Chop, chop! - Now cool, Action Boy.
鲨鱼帮要一席之地 他们很猛的
The Sharks want a piece of this world, too. And they're real down boys.
他们可能会动刀动枪的
They might ask for blades...
动枪？我的天
- zip guns. - Zip guns?
小约翰，我没说他们一定会
I ain't finalizin' and sayin' they will, Baby John.
只是说他们可能会 我们要准备好
I'm just sayin' that they might, and we gotta be prepared.
大家怎么说？
Now, what's your mood, Jets?
- 我说干吧 - 动手
- I say go, go! - I say mix!
- 打烂他们 - 扯烂他们
- I say sock 'em! - Tear them!
- 可是如果他们动到刀枪… - 算了吧
- Yeah, but if they say blades or guns... - I say let's just forget the whole thing.
- 什么？ - 你的意见呢，芮夫？
- What? - What do you say, Riff?
我们的地盘虽小 但却是我们仅有的
I say this turf is small, but it's all we got.
没错
我们要和从前一样 捍卫我们的地盘
I wanna hold it like we always held it, with skin!
如果他们用刀 我们就用刀
But if they say blades, I say blades.
如果他们动枪 我们就动枪
If they say guns, I say guns.
喷射机永远是老大
I say I want the Jets to be the number one!
- 出发！撑住一片天 - 发动了
- To sail! To hold the sky! - Then rev us off! Voom va-voom!
好，伙伴们，我们动手
Okay, cats, we rumble!
礼仪上我们要先和鲨鱼帮开会 确定战斗时间
Now... protocality calls for a war council... between us and the Sharks to set the whole thing up.
我们亲自通知伯纳多 这个坏消息
So I will personally give the bad news to Bernardo.
- 带个副手去 - 就是我了
- You gotta take a lieutenant with you. - That's me.
- 该是东尼 - 谁需要东尼？
- That's Tony. - Who needs Tony?
我们需要东尼 他的名声大过整个西城
We need Tony! He's got a rep that's bigger than the whole West Side!
- 他不再是我们一份子了 - 不要说了，猛男
- He don't belong no more. - Now, cut it, Action!
- 我和东尼创下喷射机帮的 - 现在他在那儿？
- Me and Tony started the Jets. - So where is he?
- 他的工作怎么那么烂？ - 青年会腐化了他
- How come he takes a lousy, stinkin' job? - Youth Board corrupted him.
- 暂时性的症状！等着看吧 - 记得我们打败翡翠帮的事吗？
- Yeah, temporary sickness! - Wait and see. Remember them fists the day we clobbered the Emeralds?
- 他救了我一命 - 他仍然会这么做的
- He saved my ever-loving neck! - Sure! He'll do it again, too!
他一直都帮着我们 以后也会一样
He always came through for us and he always will.
当你成为喷射机的一员 你永远都是
∮When you're a Jet you're a Jet all the way ∮
从你的第一支烟 到你死的那天
∮From your first cigarette to your last dyin' day ∮
当你是喷射机的一员 就让他们照顾你
∮When you're a Jet let 'em do what they can ∮
四海之内皆你兄弟 你是家族的一份子
∮You've got brothers around ∮ ∮You're a family man ∮
永远不寂寞 关系永远在那儿
∮You're never alone ∮ ∮You're never disconnected ∮
当你跟同伴在家 而且等着客人时
∮You're home with your own ∮ ∮When company's expected ∮
你会被保护好好的
∮You're well-protected ∮
一切都由喷射机 安排好了
∮Then you are set with a capital 'J' ∮
你不会忘记这一切的 直到你被抬走的那天
∮Which you'll never forget till they cart you away ∮
你是喷射机一员时
∮When you're a Jet ∮
你永远都是
∮You stay a ∮ ∮Jet ∮
我了解东尼就像了解自己一般 我们可以算他一份
Now, I know Tony like I know me, and I guarantee you can count him in.
- 走吧 - 去哪儿找伯纳多？
- Let's get crackin'. - Where will you find Bernardo?
- 在波多黎各人的地盘可不安全 - 去舞会那儿
- It ain't safe in PR territory. - He'll be at tonight's gym dance.
- 可是体育馆是中立区 - 我会好好对他讲的
- But the gym's neutral territory. - A-Rab, I'm gonna make nice with him.
- 只是向他下战书 - 好吧，小老爹
- I'm only gonna challenge him. - Right, daddy-o.
听着，大家盛装打扮
So listen, everybody dress up sweet and sharp.
10点时和我与东尼 在体育馆碰面
Meet Tony and me at the dance after 10:00, and walk tall!
- 我们永远抬头挺胸 - 我们是喷射机
- We always walk tall! - We're Jets!
最伟大的
The greatest!
当你是喷射机一员时 你是城里最亮眼的
∮When you're a Jet ∮ ∮You're the top cat in town ∮
你是带着皇冠的 - 金牌小子
∮You're the gold-medal kid ∮ ∮With the heavyweight crown ∮
当你是喷射机一员时 - 你可以大摇大摆
∮When you're a Jet ∮ ∮You're the swinginest thing ∮
男孩，你是一个男人 男人，你是国王
∮Little boy you're a man ∮ ∮Little man, you're a king ∮
喷射机已上紧发条 整装待发
∮The Jets are in gear ∮ ∮Our cylinders are clickin' ∮
鲨鱼帮将会片甲不留
∮The Sharks'll steer clear ∮
因为波多黎各人都是胆小鬼
∮'Cause every Puerto Rican's a lousy chicken ∮
喷射机来了 像地狱来的蝙蝠
∮Here come the Jets ∮ ∮Like a bat out of hell ∮
如果有人来挡路 他的日子不好过了
∮Someone gets in our way ∮ ∮Someone don't feel so well ∮
喷射机来了 世界为之让路
∮Here come the Jets ∮ ∮Little world, step aside ∮
最好藏到地下 快逃，快藏起来
∮Better go underground ∮ ∮Better run, better hide ∮
我们画下了界限 所以好好地藏匿吧
∮We're drawin' the line ∮ ∮So keep your noses hidden ∮
我们挂起了招牌 “严禁访客”
∮We're hangin' a sign ∮ ∮Says 'visitors forbidden' ∮
我们不是开玩笑的
∮And we ain't kiddin' ∮
喷射机来了 我们要打败
∮Here come the Jets, yeah ∮ ∮And we're gonna beat ∮
这整条街上的每一个帮派
∮Every last buggin' gang ∮ ∮On the whole buggin' street ∮
这条可爱的街上
∮On the whole buggin' ∮ ∮Ever-lovin' ∮ ∮Street ∮
Yeah!
- 东尼，你没在听我说话 - 我听得很清楚
- Tony, you're not even listenin'. - I read you loud and clear, Riff.
- 说点话嘛 - 我不想伤你感情
- Then why don't you say somethin'? - I don't wanna hurt your feelings.
- 你是我最好的朋友 - 从生到死？
- You're my buddy, my pal, my best friend! - Womb to tomb?
从生到死
Birth to earth.
所以你一定要和我一起去舞会 - 挺我一挺
That's why you gotta come to the dance tonight and stand up with me.
东尼，答应我
Come on, Tony. Just say yes.
你有没有想过一瓶汽水里 - 有多少泡泡？
Riff, did you ever stop to figure... how many bubbles there are in one bottle of this here soda pop?
- 东尼，这很重要！ - 每件事都很重要，芮夫
Tony, this is important! Everything's important, Riff...
你，我，我的老板达克
you, me, the sweet guy I work for.
鲨鱼帮不是好东西，很狠的
The Sharks walk bad. They bite hard.
- 如果现在不阻止他们- -  - 来！为生活工作
- And if we don't stop them now... - Here! Work for a living.
觉得如何？多年来 我和好朋友的家人共住
How do you like that? Four and a half years I live with a buddy and his family.
我想我很了解他
I think I'm diggin' a guy's character.
- 我对你太失望了 - 你可以结束你的苦难
Boy, am I a victim of disappointment in you! End your sufferin', little man.
你何不打包搬出去？
Why don't you just pack up your gear and move out?
因为你妈喜欢我
'Cause your ma's hot for me.
不！因为我不想 和我烦人的叔叔住
No! It's 'cause I hate livin' with my buggin' uncle!
- 少来 - 叔叔
- Come on! - Come on, uncle!
- 去吧，和喷射机去玩吧 - 为什么不？他们是最棒的
Now... go play games with the Jets. And why not? They're the greatest.
不是吗？
Ain't they?
曾经是
Were.
“曾经是” 你找到更好的吗？
You found somethin' better?
没有，还没有，可是…
No. Not yet, but...
可是什么？
But What?
你不会相信的，芮夫
You won't dig it, Riff.
试试看
So try me.
东尼，试试我会不会相信
Come on, Tony, try me.
好吧
Okay.
上个月每天晚上我都醒来…
Every single night for the last month, I wake up...
我深深地被感动了
and I'm reaching out.
- 被什么？ - 我不知道
- For what? - I don't know.
女人吗？
A dame?
就在门前，就在转角的地方…
It's right outside the door, just around the corner...
那个什么就要来了
but it's comin'.
什么东西？
What is?
我不知道，但那感觉就像 以前我是喷射机一员时一样
I don't know. It... it's like the kick I used to get from bein' a Jet.
这么说就对了 不在帮派里，你就是个孤儿
Now you're talkin'! Man, without a gang, you're an orphan.
在帮派里，你是成群结队的
With a gang, you walk in twos, threes, fours...
当你的伴都是一流的 当你是喷射机一员时…
and your crew is the best... when you're a Jet, you're out in the sun, buddy boy...
你就像沐浴在太阳之下 回到家了
you're home free home!
芮夫，我有过那样的感觉
Riff, I've had it!
东尼
Tony...
- 你看着我 - 我在看着你
Tony, look at me, will ya? - Come on, look at me. - I'm lookin' at you.
我从来没向人开口 要求过什么，是吧？
Now, I never asked the time of day from a clock, did I?
我从来没向人开口要求什么 我现在开口求你
I never asked nothin' from nobody, but I'm askin' you...
今晚来舞会
come to the dance tonight.
- 我答应达克打扫店里的 - 去了舞会再回去打扫
I promised Doc I'd clean up the store tonight. Then do it after the dance.
东尼，我已经告诉大家 你会到场的
Tony, I already told the guys you'd be there.
如果你不出现 大家会认为我很没用
If you don't show, I'll be marked lousy.
- 你告诉他们几点？ - 10点
What time'd you tell 'em? 10:00.
东尼，为了我，为了芮夫
For me, Tony, for Riff!
就10点吧
- 10:00 it is. - Womb to tomb?
- 由生至死？ - 由生至死，我会后悔这么做的
Birth to earth, and I'll live to regret this.
也许你一直等待的东西 就在舞会上出现
Who knows? Maybe what you're waitin' for'll be twitchin' at the dance tonight.
是啊，谁知道呢？
Yeah. Who knows?
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
或许吧
∮Could be ∮
谁知道呢？
∮Who knows? ∮
它很快就会出现的 我立刻就知道
∮There's somethin' due any day ∮ ∮I will know right away ∮
只要它一出现
∮Soon as it shows ∮
可能会像快速直球 由天而降
∮It may come cannonballin' down through the sky ∮
眼中发亮 就像玫瑰一般亮眼
∮Gleam in its eye, bright as a rose ∮
谁知道呢？
∮Who knows? ∮
在抓不到的地方 在街边，在海滩
∮It's only just out of reach ∮ ∮Down the block, on a beach ∮
在树下
∮Under a tree ∮
我感觉到奇就要来临 就要实现，来到我身上
∮I got a feelin' there's a miracle due ∮ ∮Gonna come true, comin' to me ∮
可能吗？ 可能的
∮Could it be? ∮ ∮Yes, it could ∮
来了，好事要来了 我等不及了
∮Something's comin', somethin' good ∮ ∮If I can wait ∮
来了 我并不知道是什么
∮Something's comin' ∮ ∮I don't know what it is ∮
但一定是很棒的
∮But it is gonna be great ∮
一拍即合 带来震撼
∮With a click ∮ ∮With a shock ∮
电话响了，有人敲门 打开门锁
∮Phone'll jingle, door'll knock ∮ ∮Open the latch ∮
来了，来了 不知道什么时候
∮Somethin's comin', don't know when ∮
但是很快，摘下月亮 一手摘下
∮But it's soon, catch the moon ∮ ∮One-handed catch ∮
就在街角了
∮Around the corner ∮
在河里轻唱
∮Or whistlin' down the river ∮
来吧，送过来
∮Come on, deliver ∮
给我
∮To me ∮
会来吗？ 是的，是它了
∮Will it be? ∮ ∮Yes, it will ∮
也许只要能稳稳地在这儿 它就会来了
∮Maybe just by holdin' still ∮ ∮It'll be there ∮
来吧，你来吧
∮Come on, somethin', come on in ∮
不要害羞 认识一个人
∮Don't be shy meet a guy ∮
拉张椅子
∮Pull up a chair ∮
风在轻吟
∮The air is hummin' ∮
好事就要来到了
∮And somethin' great is comin' ∮
谁知道呢？
∮Who knows? ∮
在抓不到的地方 在街边，在海滩
∮It's only just out of reach ∮ ∮Down the block, on a beach ∮
也许就在今夜
∮Maybe tonight ∮
- 求你，艾尼塔，你是我朋友 - 不要说了，玛丽亚
Por favor, Anita, you are my friend.
- 把领口开低一点 - 你不要再妨碍我
- Stop it, Maria. - You must make the neck lower. And you must stop heckling me.
我们可是活在现在 不是老祖母时代
We are working on our time now, not the old lady's.
一寸就好了 一寸又没有多少？
- One inch. How much can one little inch do?
太多了
- Too much.
艾尼塔，这是件舞衣 不是祈祷袍
Anita, it is now to be a dress for dancing, no longer for praying!
听着，和那些男孩一起 由跳舞开始，结局是你得祈祷
Listen, with those boys, you can start in dancing and end up praying.
请你再往下一寸
Querida, one little inch.
- 伯纳多逼我答应他的 - 伯纳多
- Bernardo made me promise! - Bernardo!
我已经来到这个国家一个月 碰到过任何新鲜事吗？
One month have I been in this country. Do I ever even touch excitement?
在这里缝衣一整天 在家里枯坐一整夜
I sew in this place all day. I sit at home all night.
我哥哥到底带我来这儿干嘛？
For what did my fine brother bring me here?
- 来嫁给奇诺 - 奇诺
- To marry Chino. - Chino.
- 我看着奇诺时，什么感觉都没有 - 你期望会有什么感觉？
- When I look at Chino, nothing happens. - What do you expect to happen?
我不知道，某种感觉
I don't know. Something.
你看着伯纳多时，有什么感觉？
What happens when you look at Bernardo?
事情都是在 我没看着他时发生的
It's when I don't look that it happens.
我想我要告诉爸妈…
I think I will tell Mama and Papa
你和伯纳多在电影院阳台上的事
about you and Nardo in the balcony...
- 我要把这撕碎 - 不
of the movies! - I will rip this to shreds! - No!
如果你能把领口弄低一点…
But if you perhaps could manage to lower the neck...
- 明年 - 我讨厌这件衣服
Next year. I hate that dress!
那就不要穿 也不要和我们去舞会
Then don't wear it, and don't come to the dance with us tonight.
不去？
Don't come?
- 至少把它染成红色的呢？ - 不行
- Could we not dye it red at least? - No, we could not.
白色是给小孩子穿的
White is for babies.
我会是唯一穿白色的- -
I will be the only one there in a white...
Sí.
好漂亮
It is a beautiful dress.
我爱你
I love you!
- 小姐们，准备好了吗？ - 伯纳多，进来，好不好看？
- Are you ready, ladies? - Nardo, come in. Is it not beautiful?
很好
Yes.
- 很好 - 我没听清楚
- Very. - I didn't quite hear.
非常美丽
Very beautiful.
奇诺，进来，不要怕
Come in, Chino. Do not be afraid.
- 这是女装店 - 等我们认识你了才会咬你
- But this is a shop for ladies. - We won't bite you till we know you better.
奇诺，今晚好好替我看着玛丽亚 你也一样，艾尼塔
Chino, you will keep both eyes on Maria tonight in case I cannot. You too, Anita.
- 我哥是只傻傻的看门狗 - 我妹妹是颗宝石
- My brother is a silly watchdog. - My sister is a precious jewel.
我是什么？刻宝石的刀
What am I? Cut glass?
最重要的是 我今晚能在舞会能玩得开心
Nardo, it is most important that I have a wonderful time at the dancing tonight.
是吗？
It is?
因为今晚是我真正…
Because tonight is the real beginning of my life...
在美国生活的开始
as a young lady of America.
Let's go!
走开
Get outta here!
Nardo. Cómo está?
奇诺
Chino. Chino!
派皮！来这儿
Pepe! Pepe! Come on, guys!
玛丽亚
Maria.
看看谁来了
Look what I got.
玛丽亚 见见我这些你还不认识的朋友
Maria, these are some of my friends you've not met.
- 嘿，闪边 - 你好
Pick up.
这位是洛可
This is Loco. - Mucho gusto. - Encantada.
- 泰芮士塔 - 我妹妹玛丽亚
- Teresita. My sister Maria. - Good evening.
- 晚安 - 这是路易士和罗莎
- And this is Luis and Rosa. - Encantada. Rosalie, ai.
Oye, Nardo.
大伙，够了
All right, boys and girls. All right.
注意，请注意
Attention, please!
注意
Attention!
过来
Come here.
谢谢，今晚来的人很多
Thank you. My, this is a fine turnout we have here tonight.
都是为你来的
It's all for you, glad hand.
我知道你们大家…
I know all of you boys and girls...
来这儿是想交新朋友…
are here because you want to make new friends...
和更加认识老朋友的
and get closer to old ones.
对
Yeah!
所以，孩子们 今晚我们要来点特别的
So, tonight, kids, we're gonna do something special.
我们来个大混合舞会
We're gonna have a get-together dance!
太帅了！美呆了
Ginger! Peachy!
好了，好了，孩子们…
All right, all right, now, kids, kids...
我要你们围成两个圈
I want you to form two circles.
- 几个？ - 两个
- How many? - Two.
男生在外圈 女生在内圈
Boys on the outside, and girls on the inside.
你在那儿？
Where are you?
好了
All right.
现在…
Now...
音乐停止之时…
when the music stops...
男生就和他面前的女生跳 好不好？
each boy dances with whichever girl is opposite, okay? Okay!
两个圈，孩子们
Two circles, kids!
试试无妨，不会痛的
Well, it won't hurt you to try.
痛！好痛
It hurts. It hurts! It hurts.
雪男
Snowboy.
I'm with it.
对啦！继续来
That's it, kids! Keep the ball rolling.
她转着圆圈，会停在那里 没人知道
Round she goes, and where she stops, nobody knows.
好了，开始了
All right, here we go.
男生在我右边，女生在我左边
Boys to my right, and girls to my left.
- 曼波！ - 曼波！
- Mambo! - Mambo!
开始！
Go!
东尼
Tony!
曼波！
Mambo!
你以为我是别人吗？
You're not thinking I'm someone else?
我知道你不是
I know you are not.
我们见过吗？
Or that we've met before?
我知道我们没见过
I know we have not.
我觉得…
I felt...
我知道从未发生过的事 就要发生了，一定会发生…
I knew something never before was gonna happen, had to happen...
- 但是比这更多 - 我的手好冷
but this is so much more. My hands are cold.
你也是
Yours, too.
好温暖
So warm.
好美
So beautiful.
美丽
Beautiful.
我相信了
It's so much to believe.
你不是开玩笑吧？
You're not making a joke?
我还没学会怎么开这种玩笑
I have not yet learned how to joke that way.
我现在知道 我永远不会开这种玩笑
I think now I never will.
- 美国佬，把手拿开 - 伯纳多
- Get your hands off, American! - Nardo!
- 离我妹妹远点 - 你妹妹？
- Stay away from my sister. - Sister?
- 你看不出来他不是我们之一吗？ - 我只看见他
- Couldn't you see he's one of them? - I saw only him.
他们向波多黎各女孩要的 只有一件事
They want one thing from a Puerto Rican girl.
- 那不是真的 - 东尼
- That's a lie! - Later, Tony!
- 走开 - 不要听他的
- Get away! - Don't listen.
她会先听我的
She'll listen to me before she listens to you.
- 如果你想解决这件事- -  - 各位，本来一切都好好的
If you two want to settle this... Please, boys! Everything was going so well.
别这样 我们都是来玩的
Now, come on! We're all here to have a good time, aren't we?
伯纳多…
Nardo...
带她出去，我们回家去
Take her out of here. We're going home.
- 伯纳多，这是我第一支舞 - 我们是一家人，走
- Nardo, it is my first dance. - Please. We are family. Now go.
来，玛丽亚
Come, Maria.
玛丽亚
Maria.
- 我不是要找你 - 我找你
- I don't want you. - I want you, though.
我找你开战前会 喷射机和鲨鱼之战
I want you for a war council. Jets and Sharks.
- 我很荣幸 - 出去外面
- The pleasure is mine. - Let's go outside.
我不会把女士们留下 和你们这种人在一起
I would not leave the ladies here alone with your kind around.
我们约在午夜
We will meet you at midnight.
在达克的糖果店？
Doc's candy store?
在那之前不要乱来
And no jazz before then.
我知道规矩…
I understand the rules...
本地土包子
native boy.
冰男
Ice.
- 午夜时在达克的糖果店，告诉大家 - 好的，小老爹
- Doc's at midnight. Spread the word. - Right, daddy-o.
玛丽亚
Maria.
我听过最悦耳的声音
∮The most beautiful sound I ever heard ∮
世上最美妙的声音 就是那一个字
∮All the beautiful sounds of the world ∮ ∮In a single word ∮
玛丽亚
∮Maria ∮
我遇上了一个名叫玛丽亚的女孩
∮I just met a girl named Maria ∮
突然之间这个名字 就再也不一样了
∮And suddenly that name ∮ ∮Will never be the same to me ∮
玛丽亚 我吻了名叫玛丽亚的女孩
∮Maria ∮ ∮I just kissed a girl named Maria ∮
突然之间 我才发现这个声音有多美妙
∮And suddenly I've found ∮ ∮How wonderful a sound can be ∮
玛丽亚
∮Maria ∮
大声说出来 如有音乐响起
∮Say it loud, and there 's music playing ∮
轻声说出来 几乎就像祈祷一样
∮Say it soft ∮ ∮And it's almost like praying ∮
玛丽亚 我会一直不停地呼唤
∮Maria ∮ ∮I'll never stop saying ∮
玛丽亚
∮Maria ∮
大声说出来 如有音乐响起
∮Say it loud, and there 's music playing ∮
轻声说出来 几乎就像祈祷一样
∮Say it soft ∮ ∮And it's almost like praying ∮
玛丽亚 我会一直不停地呼唤
∮Maria ∮ ∮I'll never stop saying ∮
玛丽亚
∮Maria ∮
我听过最美妙的声音
∮The most beautiful sound I ever heard ∮
玛丽亚
∮Maria ∮
我说这些不是要扫你的兴 或是要你听我说话
Now, I do not say these things to spoil your evening... or to hear myself talk.
- 我来这儿比你久 - 是的，伯纳多
- I am here longer than you, Maria. - Sí, Nardo.
等你结了婚，年纪大了以后…
Someday, when you're an old married woman with five kids...
你来告诉我怎么做 现在是我告诉你怎么做
you can tell me what to do. But right now it is the other way around.
- 去睡觉 - 他才是结了婚的老女人
Now go to bed. He's the old married woman.
你知道她有妈妈 也有爸爸的
You know, she has a mother. Also a father.
他们和她一样 不了解这个国家
They do not know this country any better than she does.
你才不了解呢 这儿的女孩一样可以享乐
And you do not know it at all. Girls here are free to have fun.
- 她现在美国 - 在美国的波多黎各女孩
- She is in America now. - Puerto Rico is in America now.
有时我真搞不清楚 是你的口音还是脑袋比较拙
Sometimes I don't know which is thicker, your skull or your accent.
Vámonos, muchachos!
- 让他们等 - 玛丽亚还好吗？
Let them wait. Is Maria all right?
- 我还好 - 不会再发生了
- I should be so all right. - It will not happen again.
今晚以后，事情就定了
Pepe, Indio, after tonight, things will be settled.
- 先定定你的胃吧 - 算了
- First settle your stomach. - Never mind my stomach.
- 我管的是你断头裂鼻 - 断头裂鼻？
- I mind your nose and your head broken. - Broken?
是啊，他们用玛丽亚做藉口 来发动第三次世界大战
Sure! They use Maria for an excuse to start World War III.
- 不是那样的 - 不是那样的？她只不过在跳舞
- It is more than that. - More than what? She was only dancing.
和一个其实是波兰佬的美国人
- With an American who's really a Polack.
看看谁在说话
- Says the Spic.
你不可爱
You are not so cute.
- 那个东尼很可爱 - 他有工作
- That Tony is. - And he works.
- 做跑腿的？ - 你做什么呢？
- A delivery boy. - And what are you?
我是助理
An assistant.
而且奇诺能赚 那个波兰佬赚到的一半
Sí, and Chino makes half of what the Polack makes.
广告上说“你的妈妈是波兰人 你的爸爸是瑞典人
Here comes the whole commercial! Your mother's a Pole, your father's a Swede...
只要你生在这里 不用管别的
But you were born here, that's all that you need.
你就是美国人 可是我们呢？外国人
You are an American. But us? Foreigners!
- 虱子！蟑螂 - 是真的
Lice! Cockroaches! But it's true!
我想到以前 我以为来到这儿后会是…
When I think of how I thought it would be for us here...
- 我们来时像个孩子一样- -  - 信任别人，开敞着心胸
- we came like children believing... - Trusting with our hearts open!
- 张开双臂 - 你来时是张开大嘴的
- With our arms open. - You came with your mouth open.
- 会戴着手铐回去 - 坐着凯迪拉克回去
You're the Spic, and you go back in handcuffs. I'm going back in a Cadillac.
- 有冷气 - 有小酒吧
- Air-conditioned! - Built-in bar!
- 有电话 - 还有电视
- Telephone! - And television!
色彩协调的
Compatible color.
如果你拥有这一切 为什么会想回去波多黎各？
If you had all that here, why would you wanna go back to Puerto Rico?
即使你没有这一切 为什么会想回去波多黎各？
Or even if you didn't have all that here, why would you wanna go back to Puerto Rico?
- 这儿好吗？ - 那儿好吗？
- It's so good here? - It's so good there?
我们什么都没有
We had nothing!
我们还是一样什么都没有 只是更贵了
We still have nothing, only more expensive.
- 艾尼塔乔瑟芬碧亚翠斯- -  - 不，现在只是艾尼塔了
- Anita Josefina. - No. it's plain Anita now.
- 玛格丽塔，诸如此类 - 别烦我，至少我让- -
- Margarita, et cetera. - You leave me alone. At least I let...
一天是移民，永远都是移民
Once an immigrant, always an immigrant!
- 看，她被洗脑了 - 住口
Look! Instead of a shampoo, she's been brainwashed!
她放弃了波多黎各 现在是个假美国人
Stop it! She has given up Puerto Rico, and now she's queer for Uncle Sam.
不，不是真的
No. That's not true.
我奉献给波多黎各的心
∮Puerto Rico ∮ ∮My heart's devotion ∮
让它沈在海底
∮Let it sink back in the ocean ∮
龙卷风吹不停
∮Always the hurricanes blowing ∮
人口不断增加
∮Always the population growing ∮
欠钱不断
Sí! ∮And the money owing ∮
阳光流泻 人民拼命工作
That's right. ∮And the sunlight streaming ∮ ∮And the natives steaming ∮
- 我喜欢曼哈顿岛 - 我知道你喜欢
∮I like the island Manhattan ∮
抽你的烟斗
I know you do! ∮Smoke on your pipe ∮
把它放回去
∮And put that in ∮
Olé! Olé!
我喜欢在美国 我愿意在美国
∮I like to be in America ∮ ∮Okay by me in America ∮
- 美国什么都是免费的 - 只要一小笔费用
∮Everything free in America... ∮ ∮For a small fee in America ∮ Olé!
- 用信用付帐真好好 - 看我们一眼，马上要刷两倍价钱
∮Buying on credit is so nice ∮ ∮One look at us, and they charge twice ∮
我有自己的洗衣机
∮I have my own washing machine ∮
你有什么东西可以洗呢？
∮What will you have, though, to keep clean ∮
- 高楼在美国鳞次栉比 - 凯迪拉克到处都是
∮Skyscrapers bloom in America ∮ ∮Cadillacs zoom in America ∮
- 工业在美国蓬勃发展 - 一间房里住12个人
∮industry boom in America ∮ ∮Twelve in a room in America ∮
- 许多新房子和新空间 - 更多摔在我们脸上的门
∮Lots of new housing with more space ∮ ∮Lots of doors slamming in our face ∮
- 我要买一个有阳台的公寓 - 最好去掉你的口音
∮I'll get a terrace apartment ∮ ∮Better get rid of your accent ∮
- 美国生活可以很美好 - 如果你在美国奋斗
∮Life can be bright in America ∮ ∮If you can fight in America ∮
- 美国的生活很好 - 如果你是个美国白人
∮Life is all right in America ∮ ∮If you're all-white in America ∮
美国
∮America ∮
- 在这里你是自由有尊严的 - 只要你有自己的地盘
∮Here you are free, and you have pride ∮ ∮Long as you stay on your own side ∮
- 自由地成为你想要的 - 自由地端盘子和擦鞋油
∮Free to be anything you choose ∮ ∮Free to wait tables and shine shoes ∮
美国到处都是尘埃 美国有犯罪组织
∮Everywhere grime in America ∮ ∮Organized crime in America ∮
- 在美国的日子真可怕 - 你忘了我在美国
∮Terrible time in America ∮ ∮You forget I'm in America ∮
我想我要回去波多黎各
∮I think I go back to San Juan ∮
我可以帮你找到船回去 再见
∮I know a boat you can get on ∮ ∮Bye-bye! ∮
那里每个人都会欢呼
∮Everyone there will give big cheer ∮
那里每个人都会搬来这儿
∮Everyone there will have moved here ∮
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Olé!
Muchachos. Vámonos, muchachos. Es tarde.
喂，奇诺
Es tarde! Come on! Chino!
你干什么？
What are you doing?
- 等下在屋顶和我碰面 - “等下在屋顶和我碰面”
- Meet me on the roof later. - "Meet me on the roof later."
- 要不要嘛？ - “要不要嘛？”
- Will you or won't you? - "Will you or won't you?"
来不来？
Will you?
你要去开重要的战前会 你要战前会，还是要我？
You have your big, important war council. The council...
第一，先开会…
or me? First, one...
- 然后见你 - 不，我现在是美国女孩
and then the other. No. I'm an American girl now.
- 我不等人的 - 在老家，女人都仅守本分的
I don't wait. Back home, women know their place.
在老家 小男孩不开战前会的
Back home, little boys don't have war councils.
但在这里他们会开 你要我做个美国人，不是吗？
But they do here. You want me to be an American, don't you?
晚安了 艾尼塔乔瑟芬泰瑞莎…
Buenas noches, Anita Josefina Teresita...
碧亚翠斯卡门玛葛丽塔 名字还没完呢！
Beatriz del Carmen Margarita et cetera... et cetera, et cetera!
移民
Immigrant!
Buenas noches!
- Buenas noches, Maria! - Adiós, Maria!
- 晚安，玛丽亚 - 晚安
Good night, Maria! Good night!
玛丽亚？
Maria!
- 玛丽亚 - 安静
- Maria! - Quiet.
- 下来 - 不行
- Come down! - No.
- 玛丽亚 - 拜托
- Maria! - Please.
- 会吵醒我爸妈 - 下来一分钟
My mother and father will wake up. Just for a minute.
- 一分钟不够的 - 那么下来一小时
- A minute is not enough. - For an hour, then.
- 我不能 - 那么永远吧
I cannot. Then forever. Then I'm coming up.
- 那么我上来 - 玛丽亚
Maria!
Momentito, papá.
- 看你做了什么 - 等一下，玛丽亚
- Now see what you've done? - Momentito, Maria. Cállate.
很危险的，如果伯纳多知道了- -
- It is dangerous. If Bernardo knew... - We will let him know.
我们不会让他知道的 玛丽亚，我不是他们之一
I'm not one of 'em, Maria.
但你不是我们之一 我也不是你们之一
But you are not one of us, and I am not one of you.
- 你是最美丽的- -  - 玛路卡
- To me, you're all the beautiful... - Maruca!
Sí, ya vengo, papá.
“玛路卡”
Maruca?
- 我爸给我的小名 - 我喜欢你爸，他也会喜欢我
His pet name for me. I like him, and he will like me.
不，他和伯纳多一样，很害怕
No. He's like Bernardo, afraid.
- 想想看他们竟然会怕你 - 你看吧？
- Imagine being afraid of you! - You see?
我看得见你
I see you.
玛丽亚，请你只看我一人
Oh, Maria, see only me.
只你一人
∮Only you ∮
我只看到你一人
∮You're the only thing I'll see ∮
永远
∮Forever ∮
在我眼中，在我口中 在我做的每件事里
∮In my eyes, in my words ∮ ∮And in everything I do ∮
除了你没有其他 永远
∮Nothing else but you ∮ ∮Ever ∮
对我只有玛丽亚
∮And there's nothing for me but Maria ∮
看到的每一眼都是玛丽亚
∮Every sight that I see is Maria ∮
东尼
∮Tony, Tony ∮
都是你 我的每一个念头
∮Always you ∮ ∮Every thought I'll ever know ∮
我去的每个地方，你都在那儿
∮Everywhere I go, you'll be... ∮
世上只有你和我
∮All the world is only ∮ ∮You and me ∮
今夜，今夜
∮Tonight, tonight ∮
就从今夜起
∮It all began tonight ∮
我看到了你 世界不同了
∮I saw you, and the world went away ∮
今夜，今夜
∮Tonight, tonight ∮
今夜只有你
∮There's only you tonight ∮
你的人 你做的事
∮What you are, what you do ∮
你说的话
∮What you say ∮
今天一天 我有种感觉
∮Today, all day, I had the feeling ∮
奇就要发生
∮A miracle would happen ∮
现在我知道我是对的
∮I know now I was right ∮
因为你在这儿
∮For here you are ∮
原来只是一个小世界的 成了一颗星星
∮And what was just a world is a star ∮
今夜
∮Tonight ∮
世界充满了光
∮The world is full of light ∮
日月同光 充满各处
∮With suns and moons ∮ ∮All over the place ∮
今夜，今夜
∮Tonight, tonight ∮
世界是狂野明亮的
∮The world is wild and bright ∮
发狂 火花射入空中
∮Going mad, shooting sparks into space ∮
今天这个世界只是一个住址
∮Today the world was just an address ∮
一个我住的地方
∮A place for me to live in ∮
普普通通
∮No better than all right ∮
但你来了
∮But here you are ∮
原来只是一个小世界的 成了一颗星星
∮And what was just a world is a star ∮
今夜
∮Tonight ∮
Maruca! Es tarde!
- 我不能久留，你快走吧 - 我不怕 请你快走
I cannot stay. Go quickly. - I'm not afraid! - Please.
晚安
Good night.
Buenas noches.
我爱你
I love you.
好的
Yes.
好的，赶快
Yes. Hurry.
东尼
Tony.
- 什么时候可以再见你？ - 明天
- When will I see you? - Tomorrow.
我在对街露西亚夫人 新娘店工作
I work at the bridal shop across the street. Madam Lucia's.
- 我会去找你 - 6点打烊时来 好
I'll come there. - At closing time, 6:00. - Yeah.
晚安
Good night.
东尼
Tony.
来的时候，走后门
When you come, use the back door.
Sí.
东尼
Tony.
东尼是代表什么？
What does Tony stand for?
安东
Anton.
Te adoro, Anton.
Te adoro, Maria.
晚安
∮Good night ∮
好好睡
∮Sleep well ∮
做梦的时候
∮And when you dream ∮
梦见我
∮Dream of me ∮
今夜
∮Tonight ∮
鲨鱼帮到那儿去了？ 搞不好不敢来了
Where the devil are them Sharks?- Maybe they're too chicken to show.
还有时间
- We got time, A-Rab.
- 芮夫和冰男还没到 - 来啊
- Riff and Ice ain't even here yet. - Come on, come on!
他可不用刀的 也不用原子枪的
- He don't use a switchblade. - What? - He don't even use an atomic ray gun.
- 谁不用到？ - 马文上校，天哪，我真爱他
- Who don't?- Captain Marvel. Gee, I love him.
嫁给他吧
- So marry him!
我才不结婚呢 太烦人了
I ain't never gonna get married. Too noisy.
你不会结婚的 太丑了
You ain't never gonna get married. - Too ugly.
- 砰！砰！ - 糟糕了！
- Pow! Pow!Wacko jacko!
有一个青少年毙了
Down goes a teenage hoodlum.
一把真枪可以 让你成那样吗？
Gee, could a real zip gun make you do like that?
枪能让你那样 你去穿尿布
No, the zip gun could make you do. You better wear diapers!
像你姐姐一样去街上溜溜
Go walk the streets like your sister.
听好，我教训过你两次 我可以再来一次
Listen, jailbait, I licked you twice, and I can do it again!
别这样，你们每个 分开来
Come on, Anybodys, knock it off.
- 芮夫来了 - 大家都来了吗？
- Riff's here. - Okay, cats, all present and accounted for?
我真以你为傲 你在舞会表现不错
I'm really proud of you. You did good at the dance.
- 他们人呢？ - 别那么紧张，看到东尼了呢？
- So where are they? - Unwind, Action. Any sign of Tony?
没看到
Invisible, man.
你想鲨鱼帮会要求什么？
What do you think the Sharks are gonna ask for?
求我们大发慈悲
- Mercy. - Just rubber hoses maybe.
- 也许只用橡皮水管就够了 - 放轻松
Relax, little man.
- 小老爹，你来跟他说 - 我准备好了
- You tell him, daddy-o. - I'm ready.
冷静
Easy. Cool.
去死吧！
Cracko jacko!
这么小的地方 我们需要每一个人
Riff, look, in a tight spot, you're gonna need every man you can get.
- 不 - 美国悲剧
- No. - An American tragedy.
- 砰！ - 呸
- Pow! - Poo.
喂，鲨角帮来时 你们女人走开
Look, when the Sharks come, you chicks cut out.
也许我们会离开 也许不会
We might, and then again, we might not.
这不是小孩子把戏
This ain't kid stuff, Graziella.
我和威玛也不是“小孩子把戏”
I and Velma ain't kid stuff neither.
- 对不对，威玛？ - 我们不是，谢谢你啊
- Are we, Vel? - No, thank you.
你可以说重一点
And you can punctuate it.
我们和笨蛋搅和什么啊？
What are we poopin' around with dumb broads?
- 我和威玛不是笨蛋 - 嘿，警察来了
I and Velma ain't dumb! The bulls!
- 喂 - 喂
- You. - You!
- 你叫谁？ - 谁是谁？
- Who? - Who?
谁，我吗？
Who me?
克鲁克警官，晚上好
Top of the evening, Officer Krupke.
- 你 - 谁，我吗？警官
- You. - Who, me, sir?
对，你，没听见吗？
Yeah, you. Didn't you hear me?
- 是，长官，我的听力可好呢 - 那你为什么不回答我？
Yes, sir. I got 20-20 hearing.
他妈妈要他不要回应警官
Then why didn't you answer me? His mother told him never answer back to a cop.
- 你要我带你回去吗？ - 不，长官
You little wise apple! You want me to run you in? Indeed not, sir.
我该把你们全部都带去 你们在这儿干什么？
I oughta run all youse punks in. What are ya standin' around here for, blockin' the sidewalks?
长百，我们都不敢回家 - 家里的环境很不好
You see, sir, we're afraid to go home. It's such a bad environment.
- 家里没有爱 - 好可怕
- We don't get no love there. - It's awful.
如果晚上不待在外面 我们一定会成为不良少年
If you don't leave us on the streets all night... we liable to turn into a bunch of juvenile delinquents.
舞会时你们在搞鬼 别以为瞒得过我
Listen, I know youse guys was cookin' up somethin' at the dance. So don't think you'll put nothin' over on me.
- 警官，快来，有任务了 - 快走，全部快点离开
- Sergeant, come on, quick! We got a 10-13. - Now, go on. Get a move on, all of youse.
等我回来时 不要让我看到你们
And don't let me catch none of youse around here later.
再见啦！
I'll see you around.
- 你忘了说再见 - 他们真没礼貌
You forgot to say good-bye. Them headbusters ain't got no manners.
“等我回来时 不要让我看到你们”
"And don't let me catch none of youse here later!"
- 好像我们不是人一样 - 他很生气，不是吗？
- They treat us like we ain't even human. - He was pretty mad.
怎么样？ 没事，对吧？
So, what happened? A big fat nothin', right?
如果他正好在我们 开战前会时回来怎么办？
Yeah, but suppose he comes back... while we are havin' the war council?
我们就给他好看
We'll snow him some more. See, them cops...
他们警察相信报上 所有关于我们这种人的说法
they believe everything they read in the papers about us JD's.
我们就露出来给他们看看： 让他们相信
So that's what we give 'em, somethin' to believe in.
- 你 - 谁，我吗？克鲁克警官
You!
对，就是你，给我个理由…
- Who, me, Officer Krupke? - Yeah, you! Give me one good reason...
不把你带回队上，小混混
for not draggin' you down to the station house, you punk!
亲爱的克鲁克警官 你要了解
∮Dear ∮ ∮Kindly Sergeant Krupke ∮ ∮Ya gotta understand ∮
是我们的成长背景 让我们失控的
∮It's just our bringin'-upke ∮ ∮That gets us out of hand ∮
我们的妈妈都是毒虫 爸爸都是酒鬼
∮Our mothers all are junkies ∮ ∮Our fathers all are drunks ∮
老天，我们自然都是小混混
∮Golly Moses ∮ ∮Naturally, we're punks ∮
克鲁克警官 我们好伤心
∮Officer Krupke, we're very upset ∮
从来没有得到 每个孩子都该得到的
∮We never had the love that every child oughta get ∮
我们不是不良少年 我们被误解了
∮We ain't no delinquents, we're misunderstood ∮
- 我们内心深处，还是善良的 - 还是善良的
∮Deep down inside us, there is good ∮ ∮There is good ∮
是善良的，是善良的 天真又善良
∮There is good, there is good ∮ ∮There is untapped good ∮
就像在我们里面最坏的 也有善的
∮Like, inside the worst of us is good ∮
- 真是一个感人的好故事 - 让我们告诉全世界
- That's a touchin' good story. - Let me tell it to the world!
- 去告诉法官吧 - 法官？谁做法官？
- Just tell it to the judge. - Who's gonna be the judge?
亲爱的法官大人 我的父母待我不好
∮Dear ∮ ∮Kindly judge, your honor ∮ ∮My parents treat me rough ∮
抽了一大堆大麻 却不给我一口
∮With all their marijuana ∮ ∮They won't give me a puff ∮
他们也不想生我 只是我不小心生出来了
∮They didn't wanna have me ∮ ∮But somehow I was had ∮
游手好闲的人 这是我这么坏的原因
∮Leapin' lizards! ∮ ∮That's why I'm so bad ∮
是的，克鲁克警官 您真是正直
∮Right! Officer Krupke, you're really a square ∮
这孩子不需要法官 他需要心理分析师的帮助
∮This boy don't need a judge ∮ ∮He needs an analyst's care ∮
是他的精神官能症 需要被约束
∮It's just his neurosis that ought to be curbed ∮
- 他有心理焦虑障碍 - 我有心理焦虑障碍
∮He's psychologically disturbed ∮ ∮I'm disturbed! ∮
我们心理焦虑 我们心理障碍最严重
∮We're disturbed, we're disturbed ∮ ∮We're the most disturbed ∮
就是，我们有心理障碍
∮Like, we're psychologically disturbed ∮
听着 这个法庭认为…
Hear ye! Hear ye! In the opinion of this court, this child is depraved...
这个孩子的堕落 是因为他没有一个好的家庭
on account he ain't had a normal home.
嘿，我堕落是因为我堕落
Hey, I'm depraved on account I'm deprived!
- 带他去看首席心理医生，你 - 谁，我？
So take him to a head shrinker. You!
你做首席心理医生
- Who, me? - You be the head shrinker.
我爸打我妈 我妈痛揍我
∮My ∮ ∮Daddy beats my mommy ∮ ∮My mommy clobbers me ∮
我祖父是共产党 我祖母推销茶
∮My grandpa is a Commie ∮ ∮My grandma pushes tea ∮
我姐姐长胡子 我弟弟穿裙子
∮My sister wears a mustache ∮ ∮My brother wears a dress ∮
我的老天 我难怪我一团糟
∮Goodness gracious! ∮ ∮That's why I'm a mess ∮
是的，克鲁克警官 他不该在这儿
∮Yes, Officer Krupke, he shouldn't be here ∮
这孩子不需要心理医生 他需要一份有意义的工作
∮This boy don't need a couch ∮ ∮He needs a useful career ∮
社会大大玩弄了他
∮Society's played him a terrible trick ∮
- 他得了社会病了 - 我生病了
∮Und sociologically, he's sick ∮ ∮I am sick! ∮
我们生病了，我们生病了 我们生病了，我们生病了
∮We are sick, we are sick ∮ ∮We are sick, sick, sick ∮
我们得了社会病
∮Like, we're sociologically sick ∮
我认为这孩子 不需要心理医生
In my opinion, this child does not need to have his head shrunk at all.
不良少年纯然是一个社会疾病
Juvenile delinquency is purely a social disease.
- 嘿，我得了社会病 - 带他去找社工
Hey, I got a social disease! So take him to a social vorker.
- 往哪儿去？ - 往那儿去
- Vich vay? - That vay.
和善的社工人员啊 他们叫我，“去找份工作”
∮Dear ∮ ∮Kindly social worker ∮ ∮They tell me, 'Get a job' ∮
就是叫我做个笨蛋
∮Like, be a soda jerker ∮ ∮Which means like, be a slob ∮
我不是反社会的 我只是反对工作
∮It's not I'm anti-social ∮ ∮I'm only anti-work ∮
老天啊！ 所以我是个废物
∮Gloriosky! ∮ ∮That's why I'm a jerk ∮
克鲁克警官 你又来了
∮Officer Krupke, you've done it again ∮
这孩子不需要工作 他需要被关一年
∮This boy don't need a job ∮ ∮He needs a year in the pen ∮
不是误解的问题
∮It ain't just a question of misunderstood ∮
- 在骨子里就不好！ - 我不好！
∮Deep down inside him, he's no good! ∮ ∮I'm no good! ∮
我们不好，我们不好 我们骨子里就不好
∮We're no good, We're no good ∮ ∮We're no earthly good ∮
我们之中最好的 也不是好的
∮Like, the best of us is no damn good ∮
- 问题是他很懒 - 问题是他爱喝酒
∮The trouble is he's lazy ∮ ∮The trouble is he drinks ∮
- 问题是他很疯狂 - 问题是他很臭
∮The trouble is he's crazy ∮ ∮The trouble is he stinks ∮
- 问题是正在成长 - 问题是他已经长大
∮The trouble is he's growing ∮ ∮The trouble is he's grown ∮
克鲁克 我们有我们自己的问题
∮Krupke, we've got troubles of our own ∮
克鲁克警官 我们向你下跪
∮Officer Krupke ∮ ∮We're down on our knees ∮
因为没有人要个 得社会病的人
∮'Cause no one wants a fella with a social disease ∮
天哪，克鲁克警官 我们要怎么办？
∮Officer Krupke ∮ ∮What are we to do? ∮
天哪，克鲁克警官
∮Gee, Officer Krupke ∮
克死你
∮Krup you! ∮
宵禁时间到了，各位先生女士
Curfew, gentlemen and ladies.
- 小约翰，这么晚还不睡？ - 我失眠，烦恼太多
- Aren't you up a little late, Baby John? - I got insomnia, Doc. Too many worries.
- 今晚有人看到东尼吗？ - 有啊
- Any of you seen Tony tonight? - You betcha we did.
他该来店里清扫
He was supposed to clean up the store.
或许他决定去清扫波多黎各人
Maybe he decided to clean up the PR's instead.
东尼？
Tony?
- 达克，现在不要关门 - 不关门？
- Doc, you ain't gonna close up now. - I'm not?
- 我们要在这儿开战前会 - 和谁？
- Listen, we got a war council here. - A who?
来决定武器 我们要和波多黎各人打一仗
To determine weapons. We gotta set up a mix with the PR's.
武器，你们不能打打篮球吗？
Weapons. You couldn't play basketball?
- 上道一点吧 - 你不了解
- Get with it, buster. - You don't understand.
今晚有特别的事
We got special business comin' here tonight.
- 找波多黎各人麻烦吗？ - 他们找我们麻烦
- Makin' trouble for the Puerto Ricans? - They make trouble for us.
- 你啊，麻烦还算小问题呢 - 悍卫我们地盘是很重要的
For you, trouble is a relief. We gotta stand up to 'em, Doc. It's important.
为了一个街角打斗很重要？
Fightin' over a little piece of street is so important?
- 对我们而言是的 - 对混混而言是的
- To us, it is! - To hoodlums, it is.
- 你叫谁“混混”？ - 战前会
Who you calling hoodlum? - War council... - Don't start that.
- 打架，我在你们这个年纪时- -  - 你像我们这么大时？
- Rumbles. Why, when I was your age... - When you was my age!
我爸像我这么大时，我哥像我 这么大时，你从没像我这么大过
When my old man was my age, my brother was my age... You was never my age, none of ya.
你早点知道 你早点了解（挖掘）我们
And the sooner you creeps get hip to that, the sooner you'll dig us!
- 我会帮你挖个坟 - 挖，挖，挖
I'll dig you an early grave, that's what I'll dig. Dig, dig, dig!
- 达克，每人一瓶可乐 - 谈正事吧
- Okay, Doc, set 'em up. Cokes all around. - Let's get down to business.
伯纳多还没学会 过好日子的程序
So, Bernardo hasn't learned the procedures of gracious living.
- 我也不喜欢你，废话少说 - 达克，你可以走了
I don't like you, either, so cut it. Okay, kick it, Dos.
- 大伙儿，你们不能- - ？ - 走
- Boys, couldn't you maybe talk... - Kick it!
我们向你们挑战 全面性的，一次解决，接受吗？
We challenge you to a rumble. All out, once and for all. Accept?
- 用什么方式？ - 随便你们选
On what terms?
- 你们捞过界了 - 是你们开始的
Whatever terms you're callin'. You crossed the line once too often. - You started it. - Who jumped Baby John this afternoon?
- 今天是谁揍了小约翰？ - 我刚来时是谁揍了我？
Who jumped me the first clay I moved here?
- 谁教你搬来的？ - 谁问你了？
- Who asked you to move here? - Who asked you?
- 回你老家去 - 呸
- Back where you came from. - Spies.
- 啐 - 啐
- Mick! - Wop!
我们接受
We accept.
- 时间 - 明天？
- Time? - Tomorrow?
天黑以后
After dark.
- 地点 - 公园？
- Place? - The park?
河边
The river.
高速公路下面
Under the highway.
武器
- Weapons?
- 达克！嘿，达克 - 东尼
- Doc! Doc!- Tony!
武器
- Weapons!
Weapons.
- 你们决定 - 是你们挑战的
- You call. - Your challenge.
害怕决定吗？
Afraid to call?
石头
Rocks.
皮带
Belts.
- 管子 - 罐头
- Pipes. - Cans.
- 砖头 - 球棒
- Bricks. - Bats.
- 棍子 - 铁链
- Clubs. - Chains.
瓶子，刀子，枪 一堆胆小鬼
Bottles, knives, guns! - What a coop full of chickens. - Who are you callin' chicken?
- 谁是胆小鬼？ - 物以类聚
- Every dog knows his own. - I'm calling you all chicken!
你们都是胆小鬼！硬汉丢石头的 害怕近距离
Big, tough buddy boys gotta throw bricks. Afraid to get in close?
怕肉搏受伤吗？
Afraid to slug it out? Afraid to use plain skin?
- 连垃圾都不行？ - 那不是打架
- Not even garbage? - That ain't a rumble.
- 谁说的？ - 你说要决定武器的
- Who says? - You said call weapons.
打架可以是很公平的 如果你们敢冒这个险
A rumble can be clinched by a fair fight, if you've got the guts to risk that.
一边选出一个最好的来对决
Best man from each gang to slug it out.
我很愿意冒这个险 好，公平地打一架
I would enjoy to risk that. Okay. Fair fight.
等一等 领导人说行或不行
Wait a minute! The commanders say yes or no.
公平地打一架
Fair fight.
等我把你修理完 你会像是去皮的鱼儿一般
When I get through with you, you will be like a fish after skinning.
你们最行的 和我们最行的打一架
Your best man fights our best man.
我们选他
And we pick him.
- 我以为我会和他打- -  - 你已经握手同意了
- But I thought I would be fighting with... - You shook on it.
- 是啊，我已经握手同意了 - 如果你改变心意- -
Yes. I shook on it. Look, Bernardo, if you wanna change your mind...
- 伯纳多，宝贝，来根烟吗？ - 不，谢了，我不抽烟
Bernardo, baby, would you like a cigarette? No, thank you. I don't smoke.
那是什么？
晚安，警官
Evening, Lieutenant.
我和东尼正准备打烊
I and Tony was just closing up.
各位，这才对嘛 看你们这样使我心头暖烘烘的
Now, this is more like it, fellas. Warms me all over to see you this way.
我在球场那里说了几句话后 就有这样的成效
And after only a couple of words from me at the playground. How about that?
- 介意吗？ - 不，我是个白痴
Do you mind? I have no mind. I'm the village idiot.
总部得听话这件事的话 搞不好我还能升官呢
You know, headquarters hears about this, I may even get a promotion.
伯纳多，不错嘛 我升官…
Good deal all around, Bernardo? I get a promotion...
你们波多黎各人 得到你们一直想要的：
and you Puerto Ricans get what you've been itchin' for...
使用球场，使用体育馆 街上，糖果店
use of the playground, use of the gym... the streets, the candy store.
就算他们把这里变成猪舍 又怎样呢？
So what if they do turn this whole town into a stinkin' pigsty?
别阻止他！他想回家的话 写封信回去…
Don't stop him! He wants to get home, write letters to San Juan...
告诉他们他在这儿的成就
tell 'em how he's got it made over here!
我的意思是，走人 我说，走人
What I mean is, clear out, you! I said, clear out!
是啊，我知道
Yeah, sure, I know.
这是个自由的国家，我没有权利 但我有警徽
It's a free country, and I ain't got the right. But I got a badge.
你有什么？
What do you got?
就是这么一回事，滚
Things are tough all over. Beat it!
好了，各位…
Okay, fellas...
打架地点在那儿？
where's the rumble gonna be?
来吧！正常美国人是不会- -
Come on! Regular Americans don't rub with the gold teeth unless...
- 警官- -  - 你闭嘴
- Lieutenant... - You shut your mouth!
小约翰，在你这个小滑头 被砍成两半之前说吧
Come on, Baby John. Before that smooth little kisser of yours gets out up for life.
在哪儿会面？
Now, where's it gonna be?
河边？
The river?
公园里？
The park?
我是支持你们的 我希望你们帮我扫除他们
Look, fellas, I'm for you. I want this beat cleaned up, and you can do it for me.
如果事情不顺，我甚至会帮忙你们 你们在哪里决斗？
I'll even lend a hand if things get rough. Now, where you gonna rumble?
游乐场？
The playground?
停车场？
Sweeney's lot?
你这个笨蛋 能不能放聪明点？
Why don't you get smart, you stupid hooligans?
我应该现在把你抓去关
I ought to take you to the station and throw you in the can now!
你和那些自大的移民
You and the tinhorn immigrant scum you come from!
你爸可好？
How's your old man's DT's, A-Rab?
猛男，你妈可好？
How's the action on your mother's side of the street, Action?
总有一天，会没人拉住你的
One of these days, there won't be anybody to hold you.
把他弄出去 去！滚吧！走
Get him out of here! Come on! Beat it! Go!
我会找出你们决斗的地点的
Don't worry! I'll find out where it's gonna be.
你们最好彼此收拾干净 不然我来收拾你们
So be sure to finish each other off, because if you don't, I will!
是啊
Yeah, sure.
去了解他们
Understand them.
总部老是教我们“了解”
That's what they keep telling me down at headquarters. "Understand."
试着要这些混混安份一点 结果就是如此
You try keeping hoodlums in line, and see what it does to you.
也不会让我的嘴那么坏
It wouldn't give me a mouth like his.
好了，达克
Come on, Doc.
- 别生气了 - 真是恶心
- Don't let it get you. - I'm sick.
- 你也听见了，会是公平的一架 - 从此以后就一切没事
- You heard. It's gonna be a fair fight. - And that's gonna cure somethin'?
从此以后就一切没事
From here on in, everything's gonna be all right.
- 我感觉会这样 - 你今晚去干什么？
- Got a feelin'. - What have you been takin' tonight?
我去了月球旅行 我告诉你个秘密
A trip to the moon! And I'll tell you a secret, Doc.
上面不是个男人在那儿 是个女孩
It ain't a man that's up there. it's a girl.
一位女士
A lady.
- Buenas noches, se?or - Buenas noches?
所以你促成一场公平决斗
So that's why you made it a fair fight.
- 真等不及明天和她见面 - 东尼！事情还不够糟糕吗？
I'm gonna see her tomorrow, and I can't wait. Tony! Things aren't tough enough?
- 糟糕？我恋爱了 - 你不害怕？
- Tough? Doc, I'm in love! - And you're not frightened?
我应该害怕吗？
Should I be?
不
No.
我替你们俩害怕
No, I'm frightened enough for the both of you.
- 奇诺对她做了什么？ - 奇诺？为什么是奇诺？
What has Chino done to her? Chino? Why Chino?
也许她是为我们打扮的
- Maybe she's just dolling up for us. - Gracias, querida.
我的好朋友 你们能守住秘密吗？
Rosalie, Consuelo, my adorable friends, can you keep a secret?
我最喜欢秘密了
I'm hot for secrets.
不，我不要告诉你
No. I won't tell you.
- 什么？ - “什么？”
- What? - "What?"
- 可怜的孩子疯了 - 我是疯了
The poor girl is out of her mind. I am! Crazy.
她很可能真的疯了 她看起来不太一样
She might be at that. She looks somehow different.
- 是吗？ - 我觉得她在计划着什么事
- I do? - And I think she is up to something.
我有吗？
I am?
“是吗？我有吗？” 像只鹦鹉一样
"I do? I am?" She talks like a parrot.
玛丽亚，你怎么了？
What is going on with you, Maria?
我觉得好美
∮I feel pretty ∮
好美
∮Oh, so pretty ∮
我觉得好美，好聪慧 好快活
∮I feel pretty and witty and gay ∮
而且我同情
∮And I pity ∮
所有不像我今天这般的女孩
∮Any girl who isn't me today ∮
我觉得好迷人
∮I feel charming ∮
好迷人
∮Oh, so charming ∮
这种迷人的感觉真令人紧张
∮It's alarming how charming I feel ∮
好美 几乎不能相信我是真的
∮And so pretty ∮ ∮That I hardly can believe I'm real ∮
看到镜里那位漂亮女孩吗？
∮See the pretty girl in that mirror there? ∮
那位迷人的女子会是谁呢？
∮Who can that attractive girl be? ∮
好美的脸蛋，好美的洋装 好美的笑容，好美的我
∮Such a pretty face, such a pretty dress ∮ ∮Such a pretty smile, such a pretty me! ∮
美的惊人
∮I feel stunning ∮
神魂颠倒
∮And entrancing ∮
想为欢乐而跑，而舞
∮Feel like running and dancing for joy ∮
我坠入爱河了
∮For I'm loved ∮
和一个好棒的男生
∮By a pretty wonderful boy ∮
你认识我的好友玛丽亚吗？
∮Have you met my good friend Maria? ∮
整条街上最疯的女孩
∮The craziest girl on the block ∮
你一看到她就会知道是她
∮You'll know her the minute you see her ∮
她就是那个处在 极度惊吓中的女孩
∮She's the one who is in an advanced state of shock ∮
她以为她恋爱了 她以为她在西班牙
∮She thinks she's in love, she thinks she's in Spain ∮
她不是恋爱了 她只是疯了
∮She isn't in love, she's merely insane ∮
一定是天气太热了
∮It must be the heat ∮
或是感染罕见的疾病
∮Or some rare disease ∮
或是吃了太多
∮Or too much to eat ∮
或是因为跳蚤
∮Or maybe it's fleas ∮
离她远一点
∮Keep away from her ∮
去找奇诺
∮Send for Chino ∮
这不是我们认识的玛丽亚
∮This is not the Maria we know ∮
纯洁谦虚的
∮Modest and pure ∮
有礼高雅的
∮ polite and refined ∮
成熟有教养的
∮Well-bred and mature ∮
完全疯了
∮And out of her mind ∮
- 美国小姐 - 美国小姐
America, Miss America!
发表演讲
Speech!
美国小姐，好啊！演讲
Miss America, bravo! Speech!
演讲
Speech!
我觉得好美
∮I feel pretty ∮
好美
∮Oh, so pretty ∮
本市应该赠我市钥
∮That the city should give me it's key ∮
该成立个委员会
∮A committee ∮
来表扬我
∮Should be organized to honor me ∮
我觉得好晕
∮I feel dizzy ∮
我觉得快活
∮I feel sunny ∮
快活地冒泡 很好
∮I feel fizzy and funny and fine ∮
而且好美
∮And so pretty ∮
美国小姐刚刚辞职
∮Miss America can just resign ∮
- 看到镜里那位美女吗？ - 什么镜子？在那里
∮See the pretty girl in that mirror there? ∮
- 那位美女会是谁呢？ - 那个？什么？那里？谁啊？
∮What mirror? Where? ∮ ∮Who can that attractive girl be? ∮ Which? What? Where? ∮Whom? ∮
好美的脸蛋，好美的洋装 好美的笑容，好美的我
∮Such a pretty face, such a pretty dress ∮ ∮Such a pretty smile, such a pretty me ∮ ∮Such a pretty me ∮
美的惊人
∮I feel stunning ∮ ∮I feel stunning ∮
神魂颠倒
∮And entrancing ∮ ∮And entrancing ∮
想为欢乐而跑，而舞
∮Feel like running ∮ ∮Feel like running ∮
我坠入爱河了
∮And dancing for joy ∮ ∮For I'm loved ∮
和一个好棒的男生
∮By a pretty wonderful boy ∮
你们想唱歌的话，用你的针头唱 不然就唱歌当吃饭
Cállate! Por favor, muchachas! You want to sing, do it with the needle, or you'll be out in the streets singing for your supper!
不然呢？ 我们用的是“歌者”牌缝衣机
But Madam Lucia, what can you expect? We use Singer sewing machines.
要开玩笑回家去开 不要让我听到
Sure. You make the bad joke home where I can't hear it.
走了，回家去，要关门了
- Go now. Go home. it's closing time. Shoo! - Buenas noches, Madam Lucia.
- 把窗帘拉下 - 好
- You put down the shades? - Yes.
关灯锁门
Turn off the lights, and lock the doors.
- Buenas noches, Anita. - Buenas noches.
- 牢门开了 - 我以为她永远不会走
- Adiós - The jail is open. I thought she'd never leave.
真不相信这个老巫婆 曾经像我们一样年轻
You know, it's hard to believe that old bag of a witch was once a young bag like us.
趁她改变心意回来之前 快走吧
Come on, let's go before she changes her mind and comes back.
你走，卡瑞塔 我来锁门
You go, querida. I will lock up.
- 为什么？ - 我还有工作
- Why? - I have work.
明天再做
Do it tomorrow.
- 我不急着回去 - 我急着回去
- I'm in no hurry. - I am!
我要回家洗一个 久久的泡泡浴
I'm going home now and take a nice, long bubble bath.
- 黑兰花 - 黑兰花？
- Black orchid. - Black orchid?
从头到脚
All over.
决斗之后 伯纳多和我有约
I gotta date with Nardo after the rumble.
什么决斗？
What rumble?
伯纳多的鲨鱼帮 和那些舞会上的男生
Oh...well, uh... Nardo's Sharks and those boys at the dance.
- 他们今晚决斗？ - 他们不办家家酒的
They fight each other tonight? They don't play patsy.
他们为什么一定要打架？
Why must they always fight?
你看到他们跳舞的样子 一副要赶快除掉什么的样子
You saw how they dance, like they gotta get rid of something quick.
- 他们就是那样打架的 - 要除掉什么？
That's how they fight. To get rid of what?
太多的情绪 他们要去除那些情绪
Too much feeling. And they do get rid of it.
每次打完架 你老哥就精力旺盛
Boy, after a fight, that brother of yours is so healthy.
绝对要用黑兰花
Definitely black orchid.
Buenas noches.
“你走，卡瑞塔 我来锁门”
"You go, querida. I will lock up."
说晚安太早一点了 晚上好吧
It's too early for noches. Buenas tardes.
Gracias...
他帮药房送止痛药来
buenas tardes. He just came from the drugstore to deliver aspirin.
你会需要止痛药的
You'll need it.
我们不用，我们好得很
Not us. We're fine.
- 我们乐上天了 - 你们昏头了
- We're out of the world. - You're out of your heads.
- 我们乐在云霄 - 艾尼塔看得出来
- We're 12 feet in the air. - Anita can see that.
你不会说出去吧？
You will not tell?
说什么？ 我那里知道乐在云霄是什么？
Tell what? How can I know what goes on 12 feet over my head?
你最好15分钟之内到家
You better be home in 15 minutes.
没关系，她喜欢我们
It's all right. She likes us.
- 她很担心，我也是 - 太傻了
- But she is worried, and so am I. - That's foolish.
- 你今晚会去决斗吗？ - 不会
Are you going to that rumble tonight?
你要去
- No. - Yes!
- 为什么？ - 你一定要去阻止
- Why? - You must go and stop it.
我已经阻止了 只会有两个人动拳头
I have stopped it. It'll only be a fistfight between two of 'em. Nardo...
任何打斗对我们都是不好的
Any fight is no good for us.
- 一切都是好的，我们有魔力 - 好好听我说
- Everything is good for us. We got magic. - Listen and hear me.
你一定要去阻止决斗
You must go and stop it.
- 对你这么重要？ - 是的
It means that much to you? Yes.
- 好，我会去的 - 我相信你
All right, I will, then. I believe you.
- 你的确有魔力 - 当然
- You do have magic. - Of course.
我有你
I've got you.
今晚等我阻止不是决斗的决斗以后 我来找你
And tonight, after I stop the rumble that isn't a rumble...
- 我在屋顶等你 - 不
I'll come by for you. - I will wait for you on the roof. - No.
不要在屋顶 我到你家来找你
Not the roof. I'll come to your house.
不可以，我妈妈在
You cannot. My mama.
- 我要带你来我家 - 你妈妈会怎么样？
- Then I'll take you to my house. - Your mama?
她会从厨房出来欢迎你
She'll come runnin' from the kitchen to welcome you.
- 她几乎就住在厨房里 - 穿得这么高尚？
- She lives in the kitchen. - Dressed so elegant?
我告诉她你要来，她会忍住微笑 看着你，说：
I told her you were coming. She'll look at your face. Try not to smile.
“太瘦，不过很漂亮”
She'll say, "Skinny, but pretty."
那么她很丰满罗
She is plump, no doubt?
很胖
Fat.
我像我妈，小骨架
I take after my mama. Delicate-boned.
可不要在妈妈面前
Not in front of Mama!
我希望看到我爸穿着它
I would like to see Papa in this.
妈会叫爸问你 将来前景是什么？
Mama will make him ask about your prospects.
很多
Many.
- 你上不上教堂？ - 我去
- If you go to church. - Always.
是了，爸爸可能会喜欢你
Yes, Papa might like you.
- 我可以牵您女儿的手吗？ - 他会说好
- May I have your daughter's hand? - He says, "Yes."
Gracias.
- 你妈呢？ - 我不敢问她
- And your mama? - I'm afraid to ask her.
告诉她她不会多一个女儿 她会赶走一个儿子
Tell her she's not getting a daughter. She's getting rid of a son.
- 她说好 - 她的品味很好
She says, "Yes!" She has good taste.
这儿，伴娘
Here. Maid of honor.
- 这个颜色不适合艾尼塔 - 伴郎
- That color is bad for Anita. - The best man!
我爸爸
That is my papa!
对不起，爸爸
Sorry, Papa.
芮夫，从生到死
Here we go, Riff. Womb to tomb.
你看吧，艾尼塔 不需要担心的
Now, you see, Anita? There was nothing to worry about.
看！妈妈在哭了
Look! Mama's crying already.
我，东尼，与你，玛丽亚…
I, Anton... take thee, Maria...
我，玛丽亚，与你，东尼…
I, Maria, take thee, Anton...
无论贫富…
For richer, for poorer...
在健康及生病时…
In sickness and in health...
彼此相爱相敬…
To love and to honor...
互相扶持…
To hold and to keep...
从每日到每夜…
From each sun to each moon...
从明天到以后的明天…
From tomorrow to tomorrow...
从现在到永远…
From now to forever...
直到死亡将我们分开
Till death do us part.
凭着此戒，我与你成婚
With this ring, I thee wed.
凭着此戒…
With this ring...
我与你成婚
I thee wed.
让我们的手
∮Make of our hands ∮
合为一双手
∮One hand ∮
让我们的心
∮Make of our hearts ∮
合为一颗心
∮One heart ∮
我们的誓言
∮Make of our vows ∮
最后一个誓言
∮One last vow ∮
直到死亡
∮Only death ∮
使我们分开
∮will part ∮
让我们的生命
- ∮Us now ∮ - ∮Make of our lives ∮
合而为一
∮One life ∮
日复一日
∮Day after day ∮
我们的生命
∮One life ∮
由此开始
∮Now it begins ∮
从现在开始
∮Now we start ∮
一双手
∮One hand ∮
一颗心
∮One heart ∮
- 死亡不会将我们分开 - 都死亡都不能
∮Even death won't part ∮
现在的我们
∮Us now ∮
喷射机今晚会大获全胜
∮The Jets are gonna have their day tonight ∮
∮The Jets are gonna have their way tonight ∮
波多黎各人抱怨着说 “公平的一架”
∮The Puerto Ricans grumble, 'Fair fight' ∮
但如果是他们挑衅 我们会好好教训他们的
∮But if they start a rumble, we'll rumble 'em right ∮
今晚会让他们意外的
∮We 're gonna hand 'em a surprise tonight ∮
今晚要把他们切成碎片
∮We 're gonna cut 'em down to size tonight ∮
我们说 “不要吵，不要耍花样”
∮We said, 'Okay no rumpus, no tricks' ∮
但万一他们乱来 我们准备好了
∮But just in case they jump us, we're ready to mix ∮
就在今晚
∮Tonight! ∮
今晚我们会一飞冲天 赢得漂漂亮亮的
∮We 're gonna rock it tonight ∮ ∮We're gonna jazz it up and have us a ball ∮
他们今晚会得到教训
∮They're gonna get it tonight ∮
他们的气焰越高 摔得越重
∮The more they turn it on, the harder they fall ∮
- 他们开始的 - 他们开始的
∮Well, they began it! ∮
我们要一次解决它
∮And we're the ones to stop 'em once and for all ∮
就在今晚
∮Tonight! ∮
艾尼塔今晚会很爽
∮Anita 's gonna get her kicks tonight ∮
我们会有自己的一番奋战
∮We'll have our private little mix tonight ∮
他来时会又累又兴奋 可怜的宝贝
∮He'll walk in hot and tired ∮ ∮Poor dear ∮
他累不累没关系 只要他在这儿就好
∮Don't matter if he's tired ∮ ∮As long as he's here ∮
今夜，今夜
∮Tonight, tonight ∮
不是普通的一夜
∮Won't be just any night ∮
今夜晨星不再升起
∮Tonight there will be no morning star ∮
今夜，今夜
∮Tonight, tonight ∮
今晚会见到我的爱
∮I'll see my love tonight ∮
星星为了我停驻
∮And for us ∮ ∮Stars will stop where they are ∮
今天的每分钟像一小时
∮Today the minutes seem like hours ∮
一小时过得好慢
∮The hours go so slowly ∮
天色还是亮的
∮And still the sky is light ∮
噢，月亮赶快升起
∮Moon, grow bright ∮
让这不会结束的一天
∮And make this endless  ∮
成为不会结束的一夜
∮ day endless night ∮
喷射机今晚会胜出
∮The Jets are comin' out on top tonight ∮
今晚会看到伯纳多倒下
∮We're gonna watch Bernardo drop tonight ∮
那个波多黎各笨瓜倒下
∮That Puerto Rican punk'll go down ∮
当他跪地求饶时 我们就威风了
∮And when he's hollered uncle ∮ ∮We 'll tear up the town ∮
- 我们会再回来找你 - 对
- ∮We'll be in back of you, boy ∮ - ∮Right ∮
- 你会揍扁他的 - 对
- ∮You're gonna flatten him good ∮ - ∮Right ∮
今夜晨星不再升起
∮Tonight there will be no morning star ∮
今晚我们好好乐一乐 今晚我们威风了
∮Tonight, tonight ∮
- 今晚会见到我的爱 - 今晚我们就胜了
∮We're gonna jazz it tonight ∮
- 很晚的时候 - 星星会为了我们留驻
∮And for us stars will shine ∮
今晚好好打一仗
∮We're gonna mix it tonight ∮
- 今天一分钟像一小时那么长 - 他们开始的
∮Today the minutes seem like hours ∮
- 一小时过得这么慢 - 他们开始的
∮The hours go so slowly ∮
天色还亮着
一次解决他们
∮To stop them once and for all ∮
鲨鱼帮会胜出
∮The Sharks are gonna have their way ∮
喷射机会胜出
∮The Jets are gonna have their day ∮
今晚会大大威风
∮We're gonna rock it tonight ∮
就在今夜
∮Tonight ∮
好了
- 准备好了吗？ - 好了
Ready.
好了
- 到前面来握手 - 为什么？
- Now, move in and shake hands. - For what?
本来就是这样的嘛，老弟
That's the way it's done, buddy boy.
装高尚吗？
More gracious living?
你们每个都讨厌我们每一个 我们也讨厌你们，我们开始吧
Look, every one of you hates every one of us, and we hate you back. Let's get at it.
好
- Sure.
- 开始 - 加油
- Here we go.
- 加油，冰哥 - 加油
- Let's get in there... - Come on, Ice.
- 揍他的脸 - 加油
Come on, Ice, come on!
瞪大眼睛
Keep your eyes open!
住手
Hold it!
东尼！到大伙这儿来 没事的
Tony! Get with the gang. It's all okay.
- 不 - 你干什么？
No! Tony, what are you doing?
或许他找到胆子 去打内心的交战
Maybe he has found the guts to fight his own battles.
战争不需要胆量了 我们不在打仗
It don't take guts if you got a battle. We ain't got one. None of us.
- 伯纳多，好吗？ - 东尼
- Okay, Nardo? - Tony!
等一下！先等一下 说好是你和冰哥公平打一架
Hold it! Now, let's just cool it. The deal is, a fair fight between you and Ice.
- 过去和大家在一起 - 母鸡保护小鸡？
- Come on, get with the gang. - Mother hen protecting the little one?
- 我让你打一仗 - 没问题
- I'll give you a battle. - You've got one!
我先和这个帅哥暖身 怕了吗？帅哥？没胆的人，怕了吗？
I'll take pretty boy as a warm-up. Afraid, pretty boy? Afraid, gutless?
- 怕了吗？胆小鬼 - 停
- Afraid, chicken? - Cut it!
不
No!
- 伯纳多，我不想 - 还真的呢
- I don't wanna, Bernardo. - I'm sure.
- 听着 - 你是胆小鬼吗？
- Now, listen to me. - Are you chicken?
- 没有什么要打架解决的 - 当然有
- There's no need to fight. - The hell there ain't!
- 你们都搞错了 - 胆小鬼
- You've got it wrong! - Chicken!
- 你们为什么不能了解呢？ - 了解，胆小鬼
- Why can't you understand? - Understand, chicken!
- 东尼，干掉他 - 加油
- Get out of here! - Kill him, Tony! Come on!
- 加油 - 加油
- Afraid to fight? - Come on.
- 怕打架吗？ - 加油
- 让我看看你打架 - 怎么回事？
- Let me see you fight.
- 胆小鬼 - 嘿！他是胆小鬼
- Chicken boy! He is chicken!
- 帅哥，你听听他 - 不要，住手
Pretty boy. Listen to him!
我们没什么好打的
Don't! Stop it! We got nothin' to fight about.
- 伯纳多 - 超级胆小鬼
- Bernardo! - Yellow-bellied chicken!
- 不要推我 - 来啊，胆小波兰鬼
- Don't push me! - Come on, you yellow-bellied Polack!
- 芮夫！你干什么？ - 东尼，快走
- Riff! What are you doin'? - Get outta here, Tony!
- 芮夫，不要 - 抓住他
- Riff, don't! - Hold him!
放开我
Let me go!
芮夫，不要
Riff, don't!
不要管
Keep outta this!
你们拦住他
Somebody stop him!
放开我
Let me go!
冰哥
Ice!
老虎
Tiger!
芮夫
Riff
Riff!
- 加油，伯纳多 - 拦住他
- Come on, Nardo! - Stop him!
芮夫，不要
Riff, don't!
抓住他们
Get them!
玛丽亚
Maria!
东尼，快！东尼，快
Tony, come on! Come on, Tony!
我要得快点离开这里！来
We gotta get out of here! Come on!
东尼，快！决点
Come on, Tony! Come on!
闪人了
Get outta here!
快
Come on!
东尼，快
Come on, Tony!
等我，罗莎
Wait for me, Rosa.
奇诺
Chino!
楼下没人
There was no one downstairs.
我爸妈在店里 我不知道你要来，不然我会- -
My mother and father are at the store. I didn't expect you to come by. - I would have waited down... - Maria.
- 奇诺，你打架了吗？ - 是
- You have been fighting, Chino? - Yes.
- 我很抱歉 - 这不像你
- I am sorry. - That is not like you.
- 不 - 你该回家清洗一下
- No. - You must go home and wash up.
- 明天我再看你 - 玛丽亚，在决斗时- -
- I will see you tomorrow. - Maria, at the rumble...
- 没有决斗 - 有
- There was no rumble. - There was.
- 不，你搞错了 - 没有人愿意这事发生的
- No. You are wrong. - There was. Nobody meant for it to happen.
告诉我什么事
Tell me.
很糟糕
It is bad.
多糟糕？
Very bad?
是这样的…
You see...
如果你很快说出来会容易些
It will be easier if you say it very fast.
他们打了一架
There was a fight.
伯纳多…
And Nardo...
有一把刀…
Somehow a knife...
- 纳多和另一个人，他们- -  - 东尼
- And Nardo and someone, they... - Tony.
东尼怎么了？
What happened to Tony?
奇诺，你说！东尼没事吧？
Chino, tell me! Is Tony all right?
他杀了你哥
He killed your brother!
你说谎
You are lying.
奇诺，你为什么对我说谎？
Chino, why do you lie to me?
奇诺
Chino
奇诺，真的，你在说谎！说谎 奇诺，你为什么对我说谎？
Chino, true, you are lying! Why? Why do you lie to me, Chino?
- 奇诺 - 妈妈！妈妈
Mama! Mama!
- Bernardo está muerto! - Bernardo, muerto?
不
No!
圣母玛丽亚，让它不是真的 请让它不是真的
Santa María, make it not be true. Please make it not be true.
圣母玛丽亚，我做什么都可以 让我死
Madre de Dios, I will do anything. Make me die!
只要让它不是真的
Only, please, make it not be true.
让它不是- -
Make it not be...
凶手！凶手！凶手！凶手 凶手！凶手！凶手
Killer!
我试着阻止
I tried to stop it.
我试了
I did try.
我不知道那里错了 我并没有要伤害他
I don't know what went wrong. I didn't mean to hurt him. I didn't wanna.
但芮夫就像我亲弟弟一样
But Riff's like my brother...
当伯纳多杀了他时，伯纳多 也不是故意的，我- - 我知道
when Bernardo killed him, Bernardo didn't mean it either.
我以为你知道
I thought you knew.
我不是来告诉你那个的 请你原谅我…
I didn't come to tell you that.
我才能去自首
Just for you to forgive me, so I can go to the police.
- 不 - 会很简单的
- No! - It'll be easy now.
- 我不让你去 - 我一定得去
- I won't let you! - I must.
- 留下来！陪着我 - 玛丽亚，我好爱你
- Stay! Stay with me. - Maria, I love you so much!
- 不要离开我 - 你说什么我都会做
Don't leave me! Whatever you want, I'll do.
- 抱紧我 - 永远
- Hold me! - Forever!
- 再紧一点 - 我知道会没事的
Tighten
我们现在真正在一起了
it'll be all right. I know it. We're really together now.
不是我们
But it's not us.
是我们周围的人
It's everything around us.
我带你离开 到没有人找得到的地方
Then I'll take you away, where nothing can get to us.
没有任何人
Not anyone or anything.
有一个地方
∮There's a place ∮
是我们的
∮For us ∮
某个地方
∮Somewhere ∮
属于我们的
∮A place for us ∮
宁静而平安
∮Peace and quiet ∮
空气清新
∮And open air ∮
等着我们
∮Wait for us ∮
某个地方
∮Somewhere ∮
有一个
∮There's a time ∮
属于我们的时间
∮For us ∮
有一天有属于我们的时间
∮Someday a time for us ∮
有时间好好在一起
∮Time together with time to spare ∮
有时间看着彼此 有时间彼此关心
∮Time to look ∮ ∮Time to care ∮
有一天
∮Someday ∮
在某个地方
∮Somewhere ∮
我们会找到新的生活
∮We'll find a new way of living ∮
会找到谅解的方法
∮We'll find a way of forgiving ∮
有一个地方
∮Somewhere ∮
有一个属于我们的地方
∮There's a place for us ∮
一个属于我们的时间和空间
∮A time and place for us ∮
牵着我的手 我们已经在半路上了
∮Hold my hand, and we're halfway there ∮
牵着我的手 我带着你去
∮Hold my hand ∮ ∮And I'll take you there ∮
用某种方式
∮Somehow ∮
在某一天
∮Someday ∮
在某个地方
∮Somewhere ∮
小约翰，你在这里干嘛？
Baby John, what are you doin' here?
没干嘛
Nothin'.
你干嘛在这里没干嘛？ 走啊
What are you doin' nothin' here for? Come on.
我不想让大家看到我，阿若
I don't want the guys to see me, A-Rab.
为什么？
Why not?
我在哭
I'm cryin'.
你在哭？
You are?
为什么？
What for?
- 我不知道，我只是- -  - 擤擤鼻子
- I don't know. I'm just... - Blow your nose.
- 阿若？ - 怎样？
A-Rab? Yeah?
你看到他们的脸吗？
Did you get a look at their faces?
- 什么脸？ - 你知道…
- Which faces? - You know...
决斗时芮夫和伯纳多的脸
At the rumble. Riff and Bernardo.
有
Yeah.
- 我希望那是昨天发生的 - 我也是，我好害怕
- I wish it was yesterday. - Me, too. I'm scared.
- 不要这样，听见了吗？ - 阿若，我们要怎么办？
- Cut it out. You hear me? Cut it out! - A-Rab, what are we gonna do?
我们去找大伙一起想想
We'll meet the other guys and form up. That's what we'll do.
来，我们走
Now, come on. Let's go.
- 你有没有手帕？ - 你不能用袖子吗？
You got a handkerchief first? What's wrong with your sleeve?
- 你去那儿了？ - 你以为呢？白鸟俱乐部
- Where you been? - Where do you think, the Stork Club?
- 我们以为你被抓了 - 继续
- We thought they nabbed you. - Go on.
- 有看到东尼吗？ - 没有，到处都是警察
- You didn't see Tony? - Nothin' but coppers.
- 他怎么了？ - 他没怎么了，他很好
What's wrong with him? There's nothin' wrong. He's okay, you get it?
好，好
All right, all right!
- 也许我们该回家 - 为什么？
- Maybe we oughta go home. - For what?
- 打赌他们逮到东尼了 - 不会
- Betcha they got him. - Not Tony.
- 他实在太棒了，是不是，小约翰？ - 对
- Man, he was great, right, Baby John? - Yeah.
- 他真的为喷射机出力 - 就像芮夫说他会- -
- He really come through for the Jets. - Just like Riff said he...
说他会的
Said he would.
芮夫！我要芮夫
I want Riff!
好了，葛莉拉
Come on, Graziella.
不该有人死的
Nobody was supposed to get killed.
只是…
It just...
他们要付出代价的
They're gonna pay!
- 臭鲨鱼帮 - 打架不光明
- Them stinkin' Sharks. - Dirty fighting.
- 他们开始的 - 我们来结束吧？
They started it!
- 要让他们知道谁是老大 - 喷射机才是
So why don't we finish it? We gotta show 'em who's on top.
我们搞得还不够吗？
- The Jets! Let's do it now! - Ain't we had enough?
- 怎么回事，你害怕了吗？ - 你说谁“怕了”
- What's the matter, you scared? - Who you callin' scared?
- 放开他 - 不要多管闲事
- Lay off of him. - Mind your own business.
- 不要对我大小声，我揍- -  - 你要怎么样？
Don't sound off on me. I'll...
住手
- You'll do what? - Knock it off!
闭嘴，你们这些没用的人 回家去
Shut up down there, you dirty bunch of good-for-nothings! Go home where you belong!
你说谁“没用的人” 笨大嘴
Who you callin' good-for-nothin', you loudmouth crud head?
塞住你的大嘴巴
Come down, I'll put this through your face!
- 全部进去 - 去
- Get inside! All of you! - Come on!
- 闭嘴 - 谁都不能那样对我
- Shut up! - I don't have to take that from nobody!
下一个对我大小声的家伙 - 我发誓要- -
Next creep who sounds on me, I swear the next guy...
你要笑
You'll laugh!
是啊
Yeah.
现在你们全部要尽力
Now, you all better dig this and dig it good!
不管什么事或什么人惹到你…
No matter who or what is eatin' you...
如果你露出什么你就完了
man, you show it, and you are dead!
你就是自动送上去给人宰割…
You are cuttin' a hole in yourselves for them to stick in a red-hot umbrella...
五马分尸
and open it wide!
如果你们被警方问话想过关的话
Man, you wanna get past the cops when they start askin' about tonight?
你保持冷静
You play it cool.
你们想在这生存下去吗？
You wanna live in this lousy world?
保持冷静
Play it cool.
- 我想报仇 - 冷静地报仇
- I wanna get even! - Get cool!
- 我要爆炸了 - 冷静地爆发
- I wanna bust! - Bust cool!
- 我想走了 - 冷静地走
- I wanna go! - Go cool!
疯孩子
∮Boy, boy, crazy boy ∮
孩子，保持冷静
∮Get cool, boy ∮
口袋里有火药的话
∮Got a rocket ∮ ∮In your pocket ∮
要保持非常非常的冷静
∮Keep cooly cool, boy ∮
不要激动 因为，前面还有
∮Don 't get hot ∮
好一段路要走呢
∮'Cause, man, you've got some high times ahead ∮
慢慢来 小老爹
∮Take it slow, and daddy-o ∮
你要好好活着 老了死在自己床上
∮You can live it up and die in bed ∮
疯孩子
∮Boy, boy, crazy boy ∮
不要慌张
∮Stay loose, boy ∮
轻轻地，解决它 态度轻松
∮Breeze it, buzz it, easy does it ∮
不要激动
∮Turn off the juice, boy ∮
走，走 不要像个小学生
∮Go, man, go ∮ ∮But not like a yo-yo schoolboy ∮
冷静地对待
∮Just play it cool, boy ∮
酷酷的
∮Real cool... ∮
放松，猛男
Easy, Action!
阿若，冷静 冷静，冷静
Cool it, A-Rab, cool it!
走！走！走
Go, cool!
Pow!
Go!
冷静
Cool!
- 冷静 - 走
- Cool! - Go!
- 疯了 - 冷静
- Crazy! - Cool!
- 走 - 疯了
- Go! - Crazy!
走
Go!
疯孩子
∮Boy, boy, crazy boy ∮
不要慌张
∮Stay loose, boy ∮
轻轻地，解决它 态度轻松
∮Breeze it, buzz it, easy does it ∮
关掉油门
∮Turn off the juice, boy ∮
冷静地对待
∮Just play it cool, boy ∮
酷酷的
∮Real cool ∮
好
Okay.
我们走
Let's go.
到那里去？
Where we goin'?
如果我们躲起来 警察会觉得可疑
If we lay low, the coppers are gonna smell fish.
- 所以我们第一要做的是- -  - 嘿！小老弟
- So the first thing we do... - Buddy boy!
- 回去穿裙子去 - 我的膝盖不能看，听着- -
- Go wear a skirt. - I got scabby knees. Listen...
我们到处晃来晃去 好像没事一样
First, start showing around like we got nothin' to hide.
如果他们问到决斗的事
Suppose they ask us about the rumble.
如果他们问东尼在那里 谁带了枪在找他？
Supposin' they ask you where's Tony and what party's lookin' for him with a gun!
- 你听到什么？ - 我要去找裙子穿
You know somethin'?
- 快点 - 她会知道什么？
- I know I gotta go get a skirt. - Come on, Anybodys!
很多！我知道该有人去 波多黎各人地盘打探消息
- What's the freak know? - Plenty! I figured somebody oughta infiltrate PR territory...
我很擅于隐藏
and spy around. I'm very large with shadows, you know.
我能像风一般地出入
I can slip in and out of 'em like wind through a fence.
- 她很努力地隐形 - 我是啊
- Boy, is she ever makin' the most of it. - You bet your fat "A," I am!
- 快说 - 好
- Spill it! - Okay.
我听到奇诺和鲨鱼帮 提到东尼和伯纳多妹妹的事
I hear Chino tellin' the Sharks somethin' about Tony and Bernardo's sister.
然后奇诺说 “我要干掉那个波兰佬”
And then I hear Chino say, "If it's the last thing I do, I'm gonna get that Polack."
然后他拿出了家伙
And then he pulls out the bad news!
- 天啊 - 波多黎各人就是不放手
- Them PR's won't stop. - Till we stop 'em.
- 直到我们阻止他们 - 等一下
Hold it!
听好…
Now, listen...
东尼为我们出力 我们也要帮忙他
Tony come through for us. We gotta come through for Tony.
- 我们要在奇诺之前找到他 - 干掉奇诺
- We gotta find him before Chino finds him. - And burns him.
- 你去河边，雪男，你去达克店里 - 我去巷子那
You cover the river! Snowboy, get over to Doc's.
- 我们去街上 - 公园
- I'll take the alleys. - We'll take the streets.
- 学校操场 - 游乐场
- The park. - The schoolyard.
- 走 - 我呢？
We'll take the playground. What about me?
你？做隐形人去
You? In and out of the shadows.
- 也许你会碰到东尼 - 对
- Maybe you'll find Tony in one of them. - Right!
嘿
你做的很好，小老弟
You done good, buddy boy.
谢谢你，小老爹
Thanks, daddy-o.
是谁- - ？
Who is...
玛丽亚
Maria.
玛丽亚？
玛丽亚，我是艾尼塔，你在吗？
Maria, it's Anita. You in there?
- 玛丽亚？ - 来了
- Maria? - Yes.
开门，我要找你
Open the door. I need you.
不要
No.
- 现在你也害怕了？ - 什么？
- Now you are afraid, too? - What?
我就来了
I'll be right there.
我们一起走，尽快和我碰面 我们一起远走高飞
- 一起远走高飞 - 到哪里？
- Together. - But where?
到车站 走得远远的让他们永远找不到
The bus station. We'll go so far away, they'll never find us.
- 怎么走呢？ - 达克会帮忙的，我去向他借钱
- How can we? - Doc will help us. I'll get money from him.
- 到他店里碰面 - 在达克那里，好
- You'll meet me at his store. - At Doc's, yes.
- 我等你 - 好
- I'll wait for you there. - All right.
- 玛丽亚 - 来了
Yes.
快点
Hurry!
- 玛丽亚 - 来了
Coming, Anita.
艾尼塔- -
Anita.
- 好，你知道了 - 你还是不了解
- All right, now you know. - And you still don't know.
他是他们一份子
He is one of them!
- 不是 - 是
- No, Anita! - Yes!
那样的男人杀了你哥
∮A boy like that ∮ ∮Would kill your brother ∮
忘了他 再去找别的人
∮Forget that boy and find another ∮
和你一样的人 找和你一样的人
∮One of your own kind ∮ ∮Stick to your own kind ∮
那样的男人只会 带给你伤痛
∮A boy like that will give you sorrow ∮
你会遇到别人的 明天就会
∮You'll meet another boy tomorrow ∮
一个和你一样的人 和你一样的人在一起
∮One of your own kind ∮ ∮Stick to your own kind ∮
会杀人的人不会爱人
∮A boy who kills cannot love ∮
杀人的人没有心
∮A boy who kills has no heart ∮
他得到你的人 得到你的心
∮And he's the boy who gets your love ∮ ∮And gets your heart ∮
真是聪明啊，玛丽亚 非常聪明
∮Very smart, Maria, very smart ∮
那样的男人 只想从你这儿得到一件事
∮A boy like that wants one thing only ∮
等他到手了 就会离开你
∮And when he's done, he'll leave you lonely ∮
他会杀了你的爱 他杀了我的爱
∮He'll murder your love ∮ ∮He murdered mine ∮
你等着瞧 玛丽亚，你等着
∮Just wait and see ∮ ∮Just wait, Maria ∮
- 你等着瞧 - 不，艾尼塔
∮Just wait and see ∮ ∮No, Anita, no ∮
不，艾尼塔
∮Anita, no ∮
对我来说那不是真的
∮It isn't true, not for me ∮
对你来说是真的 对我不是
∮It's true for you, not for me ∮
我听到你说的话 我的大脑知道你是对的
∮I hear your words ∮ ∮And in my head, I know they're smart ∮
可是我的心 可是我的心
∮But my heart, Anita ∮ ∮But my heart ∮
知道他们是错的
∮Knows they're wrong ∮
你该懂的 你也在恋爱中
∮You should know better ∮ ∮You were in love ∮
或着你只是说说
∮Or so you said ∮
你该了解的
∮You should know better ∮
我的爱情
∮I have a love ∮
是我仅有的
∮And it's all that I have ∮
不管是对是错
∮Right or wrong ∮
我还能怎么做
∮What else can I do? ∮
我爱他
∮I love him ∮
我是他的
∮I'm his ∮
所有事情都是他的
∮And everything he is ∮
我也一样
∮I am, too ∮
我的爱情
∮I have a love ∮
是我需要的
∮And it's all that I need ∮
不管对还是错
∮Right or wrong ∮
他需要我
∮And he needs me, too ∮
我爱他
∮I love him ∮
我们是一体的
∮We 're one ∮
不需要再做些什么了
∮There's nothing to be done ∮
我无能为力
∮Not a thing I can do ∮
只有抱着他
∮But hold him ∮
抱着他直到永远
∮Hold him forever ∮
和他在一起
∮Be with him now ∮
明天
∮Tomorrow ∮
和以后
∮And all ∮
我的一生
∮of my life ∮
当爱来的时候
∮When love comes ∮
那么地强烈
∮So strong ∮
没有对错
∮There is no right or wrong ∮
你的爱
∮Your love is ∮
是你的生命
∮Your life ∮
奇诺有枪
Chino has a gun.
我听到他们在说
I heard the boys talking.
- 他要去找东尼 - 他在达克店里等我
- He's hunting for Tony. - He is at Doc's store, waiting for me.
如果奇诺伤到他 如果他碰他，我发誓我要- -
If Chino hurts him, if he touches him, I swear to you, I'll...
- 你要像东尼对伯纳多那样？ - 我爱东尼
- You'll do what Tony did to Bernardo. - I love Tony.
我知道
I know.
我爱伯纳多
I loved Bernardo.
- 有人在家吗？ - 有
- Anybody home? - Yes.
- 我找伯纳多的妹妹 - 她不舒服
- Bernardo's sister, please. - She isn't feeling well.
谁舒服呢？
Who is?
小姐，你好
Hello, miss.
我是眩克警官，不好意思 在这种时候打扰你- -
I'm Lt. Schrank. I don't like to disturb you at a time like this...
对，的确不大方便 容我告退
Yes, a very bad time. You'll excuse me, please.
- 我有几个问题要问你 - 等我办完事
- I have a couple of questions to ask. - Afterwards, please.
- 我要去我哥那里 - 等一下
- I must go to my brother now. - Now, just one minute!
- 不能等吗？ - 不能
- Can't you wait? - No!
就现在
Now.
- 那天晚上在舞会上- -  - 这要很久吗？
You were at the dance at the gym last night... Will this take very long?
需要多久就花多久时间
As long as it has to.
对不起
Excuse me.
艾尼塔，我的头痛更严重了
Anita, my headache is much worse.
- 你能帮我去达克店里吗？ - 你们家里都没止痛药吗？
Will you go to Doc's store for me? Don't you people keep aspirin around?
那是特别的药
This is something special.
艾尼塔，你能替我跑一趟吗？
Will you go for me, Anita?
我要拿什么呢？
What shall I ask for?
达克知道
Doc will know.
告诉他我现在不能离开 不能过去…
Tell him I have been detained and can't get there right away...
不然我会自己去拿的
or I would have picked it up myself.
对不起，你刚在问什么？
Excuse me. You were asking?
那天晚上在体育馆 你哥哥和人吵了起来…
Yeah. At the gym last night, your brother got into a heavy argument...
因为他不喜欢 你跳舞的对象
because you danced with the wrong boy.
- 是的 - 那个男孩是谁？
- Yes. - Who was the boy?
- 另一个波多黎各人 - 叫什么名字？
Another from my country. And his name?
荷西
José.
- 找不到他 - 他在楼下仓库里
- Can't find him. He ain't nowhere. - He's right down there in the cellar.
- 东尼吗？ - 安安全全的
- Tony? - Safe and sound.
- 我找到他的 - 你告诉他奇诺的事了吗？
- I found him. - You warn him about Chino?
- 他在仓库里干嘛？ - 陪老鼠
- What's he doin' in the cellar? - Keepin' the mice company, stupid.
- 找不到奇诺吗？ - 找不到
- No sign of Chino? - Nothin'.
算他运气
His luck.
我再去巷子里找找 你们都在这儿等着
I'll slip out the back and check the alleys again.
- 对 - 好
- You guys hang here. - Right.
- 我好渴，达克在哪里？ - 在楼上替东尼筹钱
- Boy, I'm thirsty. Where's Doc? - Upstairs raising getaway money for Tony.
- 达克没有钱 - 他的床垫有
- Doc ain't got no money. - His mattress has.
不要废话了 拿点东西来看，放点音乐
Come on. Cut the frabberjabber. Grab some readin' matter.
你们出去街上看看 如果看到奇诺或是波多黎各人- -
Play the juke. Some of you get outside. If you see Chino or those stinkin' PR's comin...
- 我想找达克 - 他不在
- I'd like to see Doc. - He ain't here.
- 他去哪里？ - 他去银行了
- Where is he? - He went to the bank.
- 他们算错了他的帐 - 银行关门了，他在那里？
They made a mistake in his favor. The banks are closed at night. Where is he?
你知道达克很瘦 他从晚间存钱口里滑进银行了
You know how skinny Doc is. He slipped in through the night-deposit slot.
结果卡住了
And got stuck halfway in.
所以我们不知道 他何时才会回来
Which indicates there's no tellin' when he'll be back.
Buenas noches, se?orita.
你去哪？
Where you goin'?
- 楼下 - 我不是说他不在吗？
- Downstairs. - Didn't I tell you he ain't here?
我想自己亲眼看看
I'd like to see for myself.
别这样
Please.
Por favor.
- 让我过去好吗？ - 她太黑了，过不去的
- Will you let me pass? - She's too dark to pass.
- 不要 - 请不要
- Don't - Please don't.
- Por favor. - No comprende.
- Gracias. - De nada.
- 你听着 - 我们在听
Mambo! - Listen, you! - We're listenin'.
我带了口信给你朋友
Look, I gotta give a friend of yours a message.
- 我要告诉东尼- -  - 他不在这儿
- I gotta tell Tony... - He ain't here.
- 我知道他在 - 谁说的？
- I know he is. - Who says he is?
- 谁的口信 - 算了
- Who's the message from? - Never mind.
- 会是奇诺的口信吗？ - 你们不了解吗？我想帮忙
Couldn't be from Chino, could it? Don't you understand? I want to help!
- 伯纳多的女人想帮忙 - 坏人也有感情的
- Bernardo's girl wants to help? - Even a greaseball's got feelings.
- 她想帮忙逮住东尼 - 不是的
- But she wants to help get Tony. - No!
- 伯纳多的女人 - 伯纳多的猪
- Not much. Bernardo's tramp. - Bernardo's pig!
- 说谎大王 - 不要那样
- You lyin' Spic! - Don't do that.
- 金牙齿 - 耳洞
- Gold tooth! - Pierced ear!
- 不要 - 大蒜嘴
- Don't. - Garlic mouth.
- 我想帮忙 - 少来
- I want to help! - Come on!
- Go! - Chiquita!
No!
Olé! Olé!
Hey, babe!
少来
Come on!
- 抓住她 - 不，不要
Let's get her! - No, you don't.
- 来 - 来
- Come on, baby.
Come on!
住手
Stop it!
你们在干什么？
What are you doing there?
伯纳多是对的
Bernardo was right.
如果你们其中有人躺在路上流血…
If one of you... was lying in the street bleeding...
我会走过去吐口水
l'd walk by and spit on you!
- 她会告诉奇诺东尼在仓库 - 不要碰我
She'll tell Chino that Tony's in the cellar. Don't you touch me!
我有一个口信给你的 美国朋友
I got a message for your American buddy.
告诉那个杀人犯 玛丽亚不会来了
You tell that murderer that Maria's never going to meet him!
告诉他奇诺发现了他们的事…
You tell him that Chino found out about them...
他杀了她
and shot her!
她死了
She's dead!
你们这些孩子何时才会停止？
When do you kids stop?
你们让世界更糟
You make this world lousy!
不是我们
We didn't make it, Doc.
出去
Get outta here!
玛丽亚
Maria?
达克，我好像听到- - 拿到钱了
Doc, I thought I heard... You got it!
- 是，我拿到了 - 你真是个好朋友
- Yes, I got it. - Doc, you're a pal.
你是最好的好朋友 我一定尽快还给你
You're the best friend a guy ever had. I'll pay you back as soon as I can. I promise.
- 不用了 - 不，我要还你！我不能
- Forget that. - No, I'll never! I couldn't.
你知道我和玛丽亚在乡下会怎么做？
Doc, you know what we're gonna do in the country, Maria and me?
我们会用你的名字为小孩命名 即使是女孩，当你来看我们时- -
We'll have kids, and we'll name 'em all after you... even the girls, so when you visit us...
醒来吧
Wake up!
这是唯一让你听到的方法吗？
Is this the only way to get through to you...
不顾一切地去做 然后像炸弹一样地爆炸？
do just what you all do, bust like a hot water pipe?
你怎么了？
What's got into you?
你们这些孩子 为什么活得像在打仗一样？
Why do you kids live like there's a war on?
你为什么杀人？
Why do you kill?
我告诉过你是怎么发生的
I told you how it happened.
玛丽亚了解
Maria understands.
- 我以为你也了解 - 玛丽亚不了解
- I thought you did, too. - Maria understands nothing...
再也不会了
Never again.
东尼，没有玛丽亚了
There is no Maria, Tony.
什么？
What?
- 我不能 - 不，达克
- I can't. - No, no, Doc.
告诉我，怎么了？
Now, tell me. What is it?
楼上刚刚是艾尼塔
That was Anita upstairs.
奇诺发现你和玛丽亚的事…
Chino found out about you and Maria...
他杀了她
and he killed her.
No.
玛丽亚…
Maria.
不会是玛丽亚
Not Maria, Doc.
她是…
She's...
奇诺！奇诺
Chino!
出来找我，奇诺
Come and get me, too, Chino!
奇诺
Chino!
- 奇诺！出来找我，奇诺 - 东尼
- Come and get me, too! - Tony!
- 谁？ - 随便谁，进来
Who's that? - It's me, Anybodys. Come on.
离开这里
- Get out of here!
- 奇诺！来找我，奇诺 - 你在干什么？
- Chino, come and get me, damn you! - What are you doin'?
出来！奇诺
Get out of here!
跟我来，我们去找- -
Why don't you come with me? We'll find...
不是在玩游戏 你不懂吗？
It ain't playin' anymore! Can't any of you get that?
- 可是帮里- -  - 你是个女孩子！做个女孩，去吧
- But the gang... - You're a girl! Be a girl and beat it!
奇诺
Chino!
奇诺！来找我，把我也杀了吧
Come on, Chino! Get me, too!
奇诺
Chino!
奇诺！我在叫你呢
I'm callin' for you, Chino!
这里除了我没有别人 来
There's nobody here but me. Come on!
好吗？
Please, will you?
我在等你
I'm waitin' for you.
我要你来
I want you to.
玛丽亚？
Maria.
东尼
Tony!
玛丽亚
Maria.
都是我不够坚定
I didn't believe hard enough.
相爱就够了
Loving is enough.
不是在这儿
Not here.
- 他们不会让我们的 - 我们离开
- They won't let us be. - Then we'll get away.
好
Yeah.
- 我们可以 - 是的
- We can. - Yes.
- 我们会的 - 对
- We will. - Yes.
牵着我的手 我们已经在半路上了
∮Hold my hand ∮ ∮And we're halfway there ∮
牵着我的手 我带着你去
∮Hold my hand ∮ ∮And I'll take you there ∮
用某种方式
∮Somehow ∮
在某天
∮Someday ∮
某…
∮Some... ∮
退后
Stay back!
奇诺，你怎么开枪的？
How do you fire this gun, Chino?
扣这小小的板机？
Just by pulling this little trigger?
奇诺，还有几发子弹？
How many bullets are left, Chino?
够杀了你？
Enough for you?
还有你
And you?
你们全部
All of you!
你们都杀了他 还有我哥哥和芮夫
You all killed him, and my brother, and Riff...
不是用子弹和枪
not with bullets and guns.
而是用仇恨
With hate!
现在我也能杀人了 因为我也有恨
I can kill, too, because now I have hate!
奇诺？我能杀几个？几个
How many can I kill, Chino? How many?
然后还能剩一发子弹给我自己
And still have one bullet left for me?
不
No!
不要碰他
Don't you touch him!
Te adoro, Anton.